At the beginning of the story, we see a
prison built on a deserted island.
Today, new prisoners were being brought
to this prison, one of whom was Edmund.
When he met the warden, Edmund said,
"Sir, help me. I haven't done anything
wrong. I've been sent here on false
charges." The warden calmly replied, "I
know. If you had done something, you
would have been sent to a jail within
the country. Only those against whom a
conspiracy has been made are brought to
this remote prison." After that, the
warden beat him badly and then locked
him in a prison cell that had a wooden
door and a small window. This door
opened only once a year when the warden
came to beat them for no reason. Time
kept passing and Edmund became very
disturbed from being locked alone in the
cell. He had written on the wall asking
God to give him justice. But over time,
when he realized he had no control over
the situation, he started feeling deeply
sad. After spending 12 years in that
prison, he even lost his faith in God.
He thought he would be locked there for
the rest of his life. But then one day,
suddenly, the floor of his cell started
to rise. This strange event shocked
Edmund. He felt like a ghost had
appeared in front of him. After being
scared for a while, Edmund saw a man
coming out from under the ground. The
man was Abbe Faria, a prisoner from the
floor below. He had been digging a
tunnel for the last 5 years. By a twist
of fate, the tunnel opened up into
Edmund's room as if it were a sign from
God. With Abbe's arrival, Edmund finally
got someone to talk to, as he had been
going mad from being locked alone for so
long. After that, Abbe excitedly invited
Edmund to his cell. Edmund felt very
happy that he wouldn't have to spend his
time scratching marks on the wall with
stones anymore. When Edmund entered
Aay's room, he was surprised by what he
saw. Aay's cell was nothing like the
others. It looked like a decent hotel.
There were chairs for comfort, and
countless books were lying on the
shelves. Abbe promised Edmund that if he
helped him dig the tunnel, he would
teach him during their remaining time.
Edmund didn't have anything else to do
anyway, so he immediately agreed. Just
as they were about to start digging,
they heard the sound of a guard's
footsteps. Trembling with fear, Edmund
quickly ran back to his cell and
prepared the garbage basket because the
guard was about to arrive on his floor.
In this prison, the cell door opened
only twice, once to collect the garbage
and once to serve dinner. Besides that,
the rest of the day was free, which gave
them plenty of time to dig the tunnel
without worrying about getting caught.
After that, Abbe cut a small bunch of
his hair. He struck a stone to create a
spark, lit the hair, and then lit a
candle. Then, somehow they both entered
the tunnel and continued digging
forward. There was very little space
below, so digging wasn't easy. AB
estimated that if they kept working at
this pace, it would take at least three
more years to reach the outside world.
One day while resting, Edmund learned
from one of Abay's books that Abbe was
once a very skilled swordsman. After
that, Edmund became stubborn and said
that if Abbeay didn't teach him
swordsmanship, he would stop digging the
tunnel. Edmund now had only one goal in
life, to take revenge on his enemies.
After listening to him, Abbe agreed and
got ready to teach Edmund the skill of
fighting. Abbe began explaining that
speed is a warrior's greatest strength.
He thought of teaching Edmund a lesson
using the water drops falling in the
room. Standing by the edge of the
dripping water, he passed his hand
through so quickly that it didn't even
get wet. He said, "The day your hands
become this fast, you'll become a
capable warrior." After that, Abbe went
back to digging and Edmund continued
practicing. A few days later, Abbe broke
the wooden planks from the door and made
a fake sword. He then began teaching
Edmund swordsmanship properly. When the
sword training was over, Edmund would
focus on studying. Now, his whole day
was spent studying, digging, and
practicing swordsmanship. After a few
months, Edmund's swordsmanship improved
a lot. Now, Abbe started to notice that
Edmund had become an even better
swordsman than him. One evening during a
conversation, Edmund found out that Abbe
once worked for a very wealthy family
named Stadia. His master had earned a
huge fortune, and now Napoleon had
imprisoned Abbe to find out where the
treasure was hidden. Hearing this,
Edmund became very angry because he too
had once supported Napoleon. Both of
them had been locked away because of
betrayal. Day by day, their tunnel
digging was bringing them closer to
freedom. One day, they saw plant roots
in the tunnel, which made Abbe realize
they were very close to reaching the
surface. Knowing this, both of them
became very happy. But soon, something
happened that turned their happiness
into sorrow. The tunnel suddenly started
shaking and with a loud noise, many
stones and soil fell on them, burying
Abbeay underneath. Panicked, Edmmond
quickly removed the stones and pulled
Abbeay out. It turned out they had been
digging in the wrong direction. They
must have made a mistake while digging
the tunnel as even a food box had fallen
down from above. Abeay was badly injured
when a heavy stone hit his chest.
Because of the damage to his lungs, he
could die at any moment. In his final
moments, Abeay weakly told Edmund that
there was a book under a stone in his
room. Something was hidden beneath that
book, too. Edmund found the same
treasure map for which Abbe had been
imprisoned. He was shocked to see it. AB
made him promise to always use the
treasure for good and to stay away from
bad deeds as much as possible. Edmund
promised and Abbe died shortly after
that. Edmund had tears in his eyes,
feeling that he was alone once again.
Just then, the guard came to deliver
food. Edmund hid behind the wall. The
guard called out, but there was no
response. When he came inside to check
and saw Abbe's dead body, he panicked
and rushed to report it to his
superiors. Edmund quickly sealed the
tunnel's entrance and returned to his
cell. After some time, the guard
returned with some of his companions and
placed AB's body in a body bag. Edmund
was hiding in the tunnel, waiting for
them to leave. As soon as the guards
left, Edmund quietly entered the room.
He looked at Abbe's corpse, and while
staring at it, an idea came to his mind.
He quickly swapped Abbe's body with
himself. After some time, the warden
arrived with his men to collect the
body. Since the prison was on a deserted
island, they decided it was best to
throw the body into the sea. Meanwhile,
a guard went to Edmund's cell with food.
But when no one responded, even after
knocking repeatedly, he became
suspicious. He opened the door and went
inside. But instead of Edmund, he found
Abbe's body there. The guard then
shouted and went to call the warden. The
warden wanted to finish the task
quickly, and that day, strong winds were
blowing. The sea waves were crashing
against the rocks, making it hard to
hear anything. While the warden was
trying to listen to the guards, Edmund
suddenly stole the warden's keys. The
shock of it caused the warden to fall
into the sea along with Edmund. As soon
as he hit the water, Edmund quickly used
the keys to free himself. When he swam
to the surface, he looked back at the
warden. Years of anger boiled inside him
and he brutally drowned the warden in
the sea, killing him. After that, he
kept swimming far out into the ocean
without looking back. The next morning,
when Edmund woke up, he was on an
island. He didn't know how he had
survived or reached there. Even he
couldn't understand how he was still
alive, but he wasn't free yet. A group
of pirates was sitting nearby, calmly
watching him. Edmund thought he was
going to be killed. But the leader of
the pirates, Luigi, gave him a chance.
He said he would let Edmund live on one
condition. Edmund would have to fight
his traitor friend Jacob, whom they were
going to bury alive anyway. If Jacob
won, he could rejoin the pirate crew,
and they would kill Edmund. If he won,
he would be set free. Soon, the fight
between the two began. Jacob was very
skilled in swordsmanship, but Edmund's
technique learned from Abeay was
extremely powerful. Despite several
attacks, Yakob couldn't even touch
Edmund. As soon as he got an
opportunity, Edmund struck quickly and
knocked YaKob down. But instead of
killing him, Edmund turned to Luigi and
said, "Look, both of us can work for
you. We are useful men. Why kill us for
no reason? It's not easy to find good
pirates." Seeing Edmund's skill and
kindness, Luigi was pleased and spared
both their lives. During a conversation
on the ship, Edmund told the captain his
whole story. After hearing it, the
captain freed Edmund so he could fulfill
his purpose of revenge. YaKob joined
hands with Edmund. Since Edmund had
saved his life, YaKob promised that he
would always remain loyal to him. Edmund
asked Jacob to arrange a boat. Edmund
then quietly went to his old master's
house late at night, but everything had
changed. The old master didn't even
recognize him. He found out that his
father had died of grief after Edmund's
imprisonment. Edmund was deeply shocked
by this news. But the biggest blow came
when he learned that his old friend,
Montigue, had framed him and had married
his fianceé, Mercedes. The next day,
Edmund and Jacob set off for the island
where the treasure was marked on the
map. They searched every inch of the
island, but couldn't find the treasure.
Then Edmund thought there might be
something under the water. He dived into
an underground pond near the spot shown
on the map. There he discovered several
old chests. As soon as he opened one of
them, he saw glittering gold. Jacob
jumped with joy and filled the boat with
as much gold as they could carry. But to
take all the treasure, they needed a big
ship. And Edmund had no idea how to get
one. More than happiness, he was now
filled with the fire of revenge. He
decided this wealth would be used for
only one purpose: revenge. To start,
Edmund bought a big luxurious house and
presented himself as the new nobleman of
France. He invited all the surrounding
noblemen to a grand party in his
magnificent mansion. Soon, his royal
style and luxury made him famous.
Everyone was talking about him, but in
reality, Edmund was doing all this to
catch the attention of his treacherous
friend, Montigue. Montigue did come to
the party, but left without speaking to
him. Meanwhile, Jacob informed Edmund
that Montigue had a son named Albert. So
Edmund along with a beautiful woman and
some of his robber friends staged a fake
kidnapping of Albert just so Edmund
could appear as his savior. The plan
worked. Albert thought this nobleman had
saved his life. Grateful, Albert invited
Edmund to his upcoming birthday party
and requested him to attend. Edmund
pretended to hesitate but finally
agreed. At the party, Albert introduced
his father Montigue to Edmund. After 13
years, they stood face to face but
Montigue didn't recognize him. Edmund's
appearance had changed completely.
However, when Mercedes saw him, she had
a strange feeling. She couldn't
recognize him at first. But when Edmund
touched and twisted her hair in a
special way, something only he used to
do, she immediately realized who he was.
It was Edmund's old habit. Edmund knew
that Montigue was desperate for money.
So, he lied to him, saying that he had
found a huge treasure and a ship was
bringing 100 kg of gold the next day. He
also asked Magistrate Wilfford to clear
all legal hurdles so there would be no
police problems. But Wilfford was a
corrupt magistrate who had full control
over the local police. After hearing
Edmund's words, he made a plan with
Monagu. They decided to steal Edmund's
treasure before it reached him and keep
all the gold for themselves. Monagu said
he knew someone who could help them. In
fact, these three men were the same
people who had framed Edmund years ago
and sent him to prison. And now Edmund
had deliberately brought them all
together. After the party, Mercedes
sneaked into Edmund's carriage. Crying,
she told him that Monagu had lied to
her. He told her Edmund was hanged.
Edmund feared this truth might ruin his
entire plan for revenge. That's why he
told Mercedes to leave for now. Then we
see that Edmund's ship had been robbed
and it was done by Monagu's man. This
same man was also one of those
responsible for sending Edmund to jail.
Edmund burned with the desire for
revenge. The man thought he had robbed
the ship easily, but soon the guards
arrived and captured him. He tried to
escape, but Edmund showed up. The man
tried to fight, but Edmund threw a noose
around his neck before killing him.
Edmund revealed his true identity so the
man would know exactly why he was dying
and for what crime. Now Edmund's next
target was Magistrate Wilfford. Years
ago, this same magistrate had framed
Edmund in the matter of Napoleon's
letter. Ironically, the magistrate's
father had been a supporter of Napoleon.
But in his thirst for power, Wilfford
had his own father killed and blamed
Edmund for the crime, which led to his
imprisonment. This time, Edmund cleverly
made Wilfford confess everything during
a conversation. Wilfford admitted it
all, thinking Edmund had no proof. But
what he didn't know was that the police
were already in the room listening to
everything. They arrested Wilfford on
the spot. Meanwhile, Montigue, now
bankrupt, was preparing to run away, but
Mercedes refused to go with him. She
told him that Albert is not his son, but
Edmonds. When Montigue married Mercedes,
she was already pregnant. That was the
reason she agreed to marry him. Montigue
shouted in anger, but couldn't change
anything. He rushed to the fort where he
had hidden all the stolen treasure. But
when he opened the chests, they were
filled with sand. In the last chest, he
found only a small chest piece, which he
gave to Edmund. At that very moment,
Edmund appeared. Montigue now knew the
truth. Enraged, he attacked Edmund with
a sword. But Montigue was no match for
him. Edmund easily disarmed him and
pinned him to the wall. Just as Edmund
was about to deliver the final blow,
Albert stepped in and said he wouldn't
let his father die like this. Montigue
used the moment to secretly load bullets
and gunpowder into a hidden gun. Then
Mercedes came running and stopped
Edmund. She told him the truth that
Albert was actually his son. Edmund was
shocked. Just then, Montigue aimed the
gun at Edmund, but Jacob, acting fast,
threw a knife with lightning speed. The
bullet missed Edmund, but hit Mercedes
in the shoulder. Montigue used the
distraction to escape. Edmund chased
him. Montigue got on his horse and
charged at him. Edmund's sword fell and
for a moment Montigue seemed to have the
upper hand, but in the end Edmund
managed to knock Montigue down and
strike him fatally. Montigue died on the
spot. After his burning fire of revenge
finally cooled down, Edmund along with
his wife and son went back to the island
where he had spent 13 years of his life.
There he remembered his mentor Abbe
Faria. In the end, he bought the island
so that no one would have to suffer the
pain he went through. If you liked the
video, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel.