Hey friends, if you are new to the world
of the data, you might start hearing
many terms and buzzwords that might be
confusing. I have been explaining those
terms using animated sketches on my iPad
with Procreate. All of them are
handdrawn, so nothing is AI generated.
So now I have collected everything in
one video. So grab some popcorn, sit
back and enjoy the data movie. Let's go.
[music]
The role of the data analyst. So what is
a data analyst? Well, it is very simple.
You answer the business questions using
data. Think about yourself as a bridge
between the raw data and the real
business decisions. So now I can say
that I have joined like around seven
data teams and projects. And now I would
like you to understand exactly what data
analysts do in real companies. So now it
is a story time. Let's go. Okay. So now
in companies in business we have
managers, stakeholders, project leads
and their whole job is to make smart
decisions by asking critical questions.
So for example, which region is
underperforming? Why are profits down?
And should we invest here? So there are
many challenges in the business and they
need quick and smart decisions. So now
without using data, they are just
guessing. They rely on opinions, gut
feelings and many outdated informations
left and right. And there is famous
quote from William Deming I really like
and use a lot without data you are just
another person with an opinion. So that
means if your decision process is based
on opinions this has high chance to lead
to confusion wasted resources and making
bad decisions for the business.
>> I think that pretty much sums it up.
>> So now instead of guessing they have to
decide based on data. So now in
companies the data are scattered
everywhere. Your data is stored in many
different databases. There are a lot of
spreadsheets and maybe as well APIs that
provides data. So they are everywhere
and the managers of course don't have
the time or the skills in order to dive
into all those places. So that's why
they go and hire an expert specialist.
They hire the data analyst. So think
about it like you are a detective
[music] and you start gathering data
from different sources. So you go and
query the different databases and as
well pull the data from the spreadsheets
and the different APIs. So you have to
go and get the data wherever they lives.
So of course all those data are messy
and you have to go and clean and
structure those data. So maybe you're
going to go and put the data everything
in one spreadsheet like in Excel and you
start doing a lot of stuff on the data
cleaning up the data organizing it doing
a lot of calculations transformations to
get the data ready to answer the
business question. Now after you find
something meaningful from the data you
start turning the data into insights
into a visual reports because it is way
easier to communicate the result to the
stakeholders and managers using visuals.
So that means once you are ready you go
to the managers and you start presenting
the result as a story using the report
and visuals that you have prepared. Now
the managers got facts and this time
they have answers to their questions
using data. So now they are more
confident and they make better and
smarter decisions for the business. So
now you can see clearly what the data
analyst does. He or she is the bridge
between the raw data on the left side
and the business on the right side and
all what he is doing is answering the
critical business questions using the
raw data and as well it is very clear
which skills this analyst needs. So as
we understood first you will be querying
the databases in order to pull the data
and in order to talk to the data and the
databases you use SQL or sometimes we
call it SQL and we have understood as
well once you collect all the data you
will be using spreadsheet like Excel in
order to clean sort filter and do
calculations on the data so they have to
master Excel and after analyzing the
data using the spreadsheet you need a
data visualization skills using tools
like maybe PowerBI or Tableau To create
charts and clear visuals to be reported
to the managers and of course one very
important skill and crucial you must
clearly understand the business
questions from the managers and
communicate the results and the findings
very effectively. So you have to master
this skill. You have to tell a story
behind the data. So you need really very
good communication skills. So that means
if you master those skills you will be
an amazing data analyst that's going to
help the company and the managers making
the smart decisions. [music] And now my
friends we have an issue. This might
work for a small company [music] but it
will not work for a modern big companies
and here's why. Now big companies
generates big data and it's going to be
really hard for the data analyst to
manually extract the data for analyzers
because you're going to need a lot of
data and your request going to take like
hours and even days to get the data and
it might crash and it going to be
sometimes impossible to get the data. So
it's going to be for you as a data
analyst really hard to answer any
questions and your process going to take
weeks until you give any answers and of
course managers cannot wait for weeks in
order to get like an answer. So my
friend this approach will not work. This
is simply does not scale. So now we have
to go and scale things and hire new
people. Now a data architect it's like
an architect of a building. You have to
design the blueprint of a scalable data
system and you have to go and organize
the data into multiple layers. Like for
example the medelian architecture you
have a bronze layer for the raw data and
a server layer for a clean data and a
gold and very important layer for clean
structured and optimized data. So all
what the data architect is doing is
designing this scalable data system. So
now as you can see the data architect is
designing this scalable data system but
as usual they are not the one that is
building it. For that we need another
experts and we call them the data
engineers. So now as a data engineer
you're going to go and build something
called data pipelines. Well it's all
about to connect to multiple source
systems and start automatically moving
the data from the sources to the new
data system and as well very important
the data must move quickly. So the
pipeline's going to bring the data to
the first layer to the bronze layer as a
row data. Nothing fancy going to happen
here. Then the data engineer going to
move the data to the server layer and
there the data get cleaned, structured
and prepared for the final layer. Now in
the final layer, the data engineer going
to go and build a data model which is
highly organized and optimized model
that is perfectly made for quick
analyzes. And we have with that a
process that runs automatically from the
source systems until the final layer.
And this runs every day very fast and in
some scenarios as a stream like a real
life data. So remember now our data
analyst friend. So now, thanks to the
data architect and the data engineer,
analysts life now is way easier. No more
nightmare of pulling the data manually
from the source system. No need anymore
for the spreadsheets and the Excel
lists. Now everything is prepared for
the data analyst to BE FAST.
>> HELL YEAH. HEY, COME ON, BABY. COME ON.
YES. COME ON.
SO now again as a data analyst once you
get a question from the business you can
go quickly and straight away to the code
layer where everything is prepared and
now using SQL you will be querying the
data model in the go layer in order to
explore and try to find answers for the
question. So once you find it, you will
go and build again like a visual report
and tell a story for the managers. And
with this setup, you only focus on what
matters when finding answers for the
business. And this can speed the whole
process for you and you will be ready to
answer quickly the questions. Now I'm
really sorry we are not done yet. There
[music] is still an issue in this story.
Now all you are doing here as a data
analyst is that you are answering ad hoc
questions and your answers are always
like one-time reports. But what can
happen for sure is that one or few
reports going to deliver really an
incredible value and it is not just
useful for once and only for the
managers. Many people across the company
going to be interested in this report.
So you're going to have a new user
groups that going to ask you one
question. I want your report EVERY DAY.
>> NO. GOD PLEASE NO. NO. AND THE nightmare
going to come back where you have every
day to run the same query and generate
the same reports and you're going to
daily send this reports to the users and
this going to be total waste of your
time and going to build huge stress on
you and that's why companies going to
bring another person to the data team
and this time we're going to have the
business intelligence developer or BI
developer. So once the BI developer
joins you as a data analyst going to say
hey go and automate this report and make
it visible for many users. So first the
BI developer going to build an
environment like a server where the
dashboards and reports going to live.
This must be secure and has an access
management. Sometimes you cannot give
all the data for everyone in the
company. And as well this server must be
accessible 24/7. So the report and
dashboard must be always available. So
once the reporting server is there the
BI developer going to take everything
the report the logic and build from it
something called interactive dashboard
and what is very important this
dashboard going to be automatically
connected to the gold layer to the data
model so that every day and this is
important the dashboard and the reports
going to get fresh data from the data
system from the gold layer and once
everything is live the user is going to
go and start requesting access to the
reports and start accessing the
dashboards and the data everything is
highly automated and scalable. So the
data going to flow from the sources into
the different layers of our data system
and as well automatically flowing to the
reporting server and refreshing the data
there. So this is the big differences
between the data analyst and the BI
developer. The data analyst is the one
that is bringing the first report and
insights and once a visual or a report
gets very important. The BI developer
[music] is the one that is responsible
of making this report accessible,
scalable and everyday available for many
users. Now, so far we have held the
business and the managers with questions
that are about the past and the present.
What happened? How much did we sell? Why
did sale drop? But at some point the
managers can ask bigger questions.
Questions about the future. What will
happen next month? Can we predict which
customers might leave us? What can
happen if we change our pricing
strategy? So, they are advanced
questions about the future. And to be
honest, the data analysts don't have the
tools in order to answer them. And for
that, we need another expert called the
data scientist. This is Sheldor the
Conqueror. We are about to enter Axel's
fortress.
>> The data scientist is the one that going
to use the data in order to build and
train models. They going to do a lot of
experiments. So at the end the
scientists going to use this model in
order to give answers for the future. So
with that the managers are not just
informed they are as well prepared for
the future. They are proactively making
decisions. They stay ahead of the
competition and as well they tackle
challenges before they even appear. Now
this type of work is very important
thing not only for the managers and
projects leads this is important for
everyone else. Now this model this work
from the data scientist must be visible
for other users and this is the same
thing that happens before right with the
BI developer but now we need another
type we have the machine learning
developer ML developer. So now what they
going to do they're going to as well
prepare a server and environments to run
and deploy the model from the data
scientist. So they're going to go and
put it in productive environments and
everything going to be now automatically
secure, scalable and available 24/7. And
the result of this model could be
presented in like an application to show
the result of the productions for
everyone or as well sometimes they show
it in dashboards and reports. So their
job is to make the result of this model
available in many services in the
company and accessible by other users
and build by the ML engineer and with
that everyone from the managers to teams
across the company benefits from
advanced predictions every day and
anytime. So now by looking to this
everything is highly automated. The data
going to flow from the sources to the
data system and then flows to the
reports and dashboards and as well
automatically flow to our model that is
trained from the data analyst and built
from the ML engineer. So this is what a
modern big company built. They build
scalable data system. Now if you look to
this you can see there is a pattern. You
can see the data architect is working
closely to the data engineer to build
the data system. The data analyst works
as well closely to the BI developer in
order to build this reporting system and
the data scientist together with the ML
engineer. They work on building an
advanced analytical system. And there is
actually another pattern. You can see in
those roles there is always somebody is
like doing a design like the data
architect is like designing the data
system and the data analyst is like
building the first version of the
reports. Same thing for the data
scientist is the one that is
experimenting and training the first
version of the model. So those one are
always like trying to discover trying to
put the blueprint. And now in the other
side we have the other category you have
the persons that are building it
bringing it to a productive scalable
environment and making things live. Like
the data engineer is the one that builds
the data pipelines and this data system.
The BI developer is bringing the reports
and dashboards into scalable and
productive reporting system and the
machine learning engineer is the one
that is bringing the model and deploy
[music] it into a productive system and
offering the results in different
services. So they are the engineers,
they are the developers. So this is what
a real modern data team looks like.
All right. Now the story with the data
always start with a problem in the
business. So we have a business question
like for example how many customers do
we have in the last quarter. Now of
course it is smart thing to ask the data
instead of having gut feelings about the
problem. That's why we try to get the
answer from the data and for that we
hire the data analyst. So now the data
and is going to open their tools and
start pulling the data from different
sources maybe from the sales system
customers database and product logs and
of course they are in between many steps
but at the end the data analyst is
building a report a dashboard using BI
tools like PowerBI or Tableau and of
course using visuals it is always easier
to deliver the message the story behind
the data for the business users and now
once everything is ready the data
analyst going to go and present the
result for the business users but Now
this going to scare everyone. The trends
is going down. We are losing customers
in the last 3 months and everyone starts
to panic. And now what can happen? Of
course, one of the managers going to ask
a very important question. Can we
predict how many customers are going to
leave in the future? So which customers
are likely to leave so that we can take
an action maybe in order to prevent
that? And now if the managers go and ask
the data analyst about the predictions,
highly likely you will get an answer
like this. Well, I have only PowerBI. I
can only show you the data for the
current situation or the history, but I
can't make something very intelligent in
order to predict things in the future.
And my friends, exactly for this
scenario as we get more complicated and
advanced questions. We need a data
expert, a data specialist in order to
solve this problem. And here comes the
data scientist. So that means if the
business question is all about the
current situation or maybe the past and
the history then we need a data analyst
in order to do something called
descriptive analyszis. But now if the
question is looking to the future then
we need a data scientist in order to do
predictive analyszis and of course this
type of analyszis it is way more complex
than the descriptive analyzes and for
that we need like an intelligence system
using tools like PowerBI Tableau SQL
will not really help. So now let's see
how our friend the data scientist going
to solve this problem. Now of course for
each problem we need always data. That's
why the first step is to collect the
data. But now this time the data
scientist needs way more data than the
data analyst. So anything the company is
generating about the customers going to
be important in this phase. So the data
going to get extracted from databases,
logs, spreadsheets. So everything that
is related to this issue going to be
collected in one place. So now of course
all those sources speaks different
languages and they structure and store
their data differently. So that means
the data stinks the data is chaotic and
it's time to get hands dirty. So that
means in this phase we are doing data
preparations or let's say like
pre-processing like for example we can
go and merge those files together and
the sources using joins and we have to
check the content of the data. If there
are a lot of nulls we can go and replace
them with something more meaningful. And
another thing that we can do is that we
can correct the data types. Maybe remove
the duplicates. Maybe they are like
columns that are totally useless. Now
this tip is really time consuming. Like
you spend 70 time of your total projects
only doing those stuff only cleaning and
preparing the data for the next steps.
And of course if you are lucky and have
a data engineer like me in your
projects, then we're going to go and
prepare all those stuff for the data
scientist so that the data scientist
only focus on the next steps. But you
don't have this luxury in each company.
That's why mostly you'll end up doing
those stuff. All right. So with that, we
have now a perfect data set that is
clean, structured, and ready for the
next steps. And now you might get
excited and say yes. Now we're going to
go and do some magic, some AI and
machine learning, right? Well, I have to
stop you there. Before we touch anything
about machine learning, we have to do
something very important. We have to
explore and understand the data. So we
have to do something called exploratory
data analyszis. So what we're going to
do we're going to go and open our
notebooks and start asking questions
like for example how the data is
distributed how we can cluster the
customers is there like any outliers
what are the relationship between like
different measures. So with that you are
exploring and understand the content of
the data and this is something that we
will not go and share with the
stakeholders. This step we do it for us
the data scientist in order to
understand the data. It's like doctors
they read the charts before doing any
diagnosis. Right? So it's like a
thinking phase. You look at the data,
ask questions and make notes. So now
once we have a good feeling about the
data and we feel confident, we can move
to the next step. And the next one is
very powerful but yet very underrated.
Sadly a lot of data scientists skip
this. Now the scenario is like this. The
data set that we have is yes clean
prepared but the data itself it is very
row. It is not yet like an information
like for example you could have a column
called the sign up date of the customer.
Now this is very row instead we can make
like an extra column. We can derive new
column and we calculate the days since
the sign up. So that means we are
creating new columns. We are deriving
informations from the row data and we
can create other measures like for
example the total spent by customers the
average session duration. So we are
creating deriving smart columns that
don't exist on the original data set and
of course they are not easy to create.
You need some domain and business
knowledge. That's why we have done the
ADA phase right and this is very
important. I really don't get it why
some skip this phase. the quality of the
features that you add to the data set
gonna decide really the outcomes of your
work. So this is what we mean with the
feature engineering. We are deriving
important informations from our row data
set. And now my friends with that we
have everything. We are ready and it is
magic time. So it is time to do some
machine learning. So now the first step
is that we're going to go and split our
data sets into two sets. The first one
is the training set where our model
going to learn from. And the second one
is a smaller one, the test set. We're
going to use it in order to test the
performance the output of our model.
Because if you train and test at the
same data set, basically you are
cheating. So we don't do that. We split
the data sets. And now the next step is
the most important one. We have to
choose an algorithm. An algorithm it's
like a set of mathematical steps that
describes how to learn from data. So
basically this is completely mathematics
and what we have to do is that to
understand those algorithms because we
have many different algorithms and we
have to pick the right one for the right
problem. So now once you picked this
algorithm the next step is that to go
and apply the training data sets on the
algorithm. So now we are combining
mathematics with data. So the algorithm
going to go through all your data and
start learning from the data sets and
this is what we call my friend training
a model. Now that means the model going
to start learning the patterns. It's
going to go and find connections and
relationships between the data and going
to start adjusting itself as well to
minimize the errors. So that at the end
we get something very powerful called a
trained model that we could use in order
to do predictions for new data. Now the
output of this trained model going to be
predictions. So it could be like yes the
customer is likely to stay or no this
customer might leave soon. So we are
labeling each customer or we could have
like percentage on how likely the
customer going to leave. Now of course
we have to share now this knowledge to
the business users. What we could do we
could import everything the data and the
predictions in PowerBI or Tableau and
build again like a visual in order to
show the final results. So as you can
see it's always nice thing to
communicate with the business users
using PI tools because they are very
friendly compared to maybe like visual
inside your notebook. So now we go and
present the results for the business
users and now they have more
understanding what could happen in the
future. Now next what going to happen
they going to plan actions. So maybe
they're going to go and launch retention
campaign or maybe sends a new offers to
the risky customers or maybe the sales
team going to go and reach them
directly. And this is the most beautiful
moment as a data scientist. You see you
are adding value to the company. You are
not just building like a fancy model
because you could. You are really
helping the business to see what is
coming and to do something about it. Now
this sounds like an happy end, right?
You have delivered your work. You have
improved the business and that's it. But
sadly the bad news is that we are not
done yet. So far everything that we have
done is manually and as well like we can
call it prototyping. But now of course
this is not one-time activity. We have
to continue doing those stuff and you
cannot keep doing everything like
manually on your notebook. And of course
the sources keep generating new data
every day and maybe they are useful
informations that you have to train the
model again. So now we are at a point
where we have to automate everything and
make deployments. Deployments means we
take everything that we have done
manually so far and put it in real
automated system. [clears throat] This
system of course should not run locally
at your notebook. We have to run it on
servers for example in the cloud. And of
course what we can do we can use APIs in
order to connect internal applications
and system in the company to the model
in order to show those scores at the
front end. So the whole thing is all
about to bring everything that you have
done manually at your notebook and to
deploy it to professional platform that
is fully automated, scalable, highly
available and secure and connectable to
different applications at your business.
And if you are lucky enough and you have
ML engineers or ML ops, they have to do
those stuff. So as a data scientist,
actually this is not the thing that we
do. But if you don't have them, then you
have to do it in your own. So now my
friends everything that you have just
seen like collecting the data, preparing
the data, training the model, this is
what we call classical machine learning
process because we are now in 2025 and
we have entered the world of pre-trained
models especially the LLMs large
language models like TBT cloud mist and
others they are models that already
trained on massive amount of data in the
internet on public data like text
website documents and They already
understand the language, context and
reasoning. And this is really crazy
because before we have like models and
we have always to train the models but
now everything is prepared for you. We
have models and as well they are
pre-trained with massive amount of data.
But now you might say yeah okay those
pre-trained models are really good but
they are very like generic. They trained
on the public data. In the companies we
have like special data. Well it's fine
because most of those models they allow
something called finetuning. So that
means you can go and pick one of those
pre-trained models and train it,
fine-tune it with the company's data and
with that you make it smart with your
domain, with your business. And now you
might ask, okay, why we need all those
LLMs? Well, think about it like this. If
each time the stackholder or manager
need like new reports or new
informations from the model and you go
and jump and get the data from the
model, put it in PowerBI and then
present it for the stakeholders. This is
really slow. So instead what we can do
we let the user have a chat with the
model and the users could start
conversations like for example why are
customers leaving a region B summarize
all the feedback from the cancelled
users so they're going to have like a
chat with the model and this is way
better than waiting each time for your
PowerBI report and for that we could use
the help of those pre-trained models the
LLMs and now of course comes the scary
part where you ask if we have all those
pre-trained models why Do we have even
data scientists? I understood from you.
We need data scientists in order to
train models. But if we have pre-trained
models, why do we need them? Well, first
of all, my friends, everything that I
have described is the industrial data
scientist. So, someone is hired in the
company to do those stuff. But the one
that pre-trained those data models, they
are as well data scientists, but they
are not hired from the industry. They
are actually researchers. And of course
they work in massive engineering teams
in big tech companies like OpenAI,
Google, Meta and they do the amazing
work of bringing those pre-trained
models in the market. And from the other
side of course we still need the
industrial data science for one very
important reason. Well my friends all
those LLMs and pre-trained models they
are trained on public data and most of
the companies they don't bring the data
on public they all internal confidential
and even secrets. So there will be a lot
of business problems that depends on the
company's data and as long as the
companies protect their data. We're
going to end up in the situation where
we need to hire data scientist in the
industry so that they either fine-tune
the pre-trained models or in many
scenarios they have to train from the
scratch the models using the company's
data. And that's why the data scientist
in the industry is very relevant. And to
be honest, we have now a lot of work to
do because we suddenly exposed to all
those pre-trained models and we have to
fine-tune a lot of new models. So I am
very positive and excited about it that
this going to accelerate our work. This
going to open the door for many use
cases that I never thought before. And
believe me, we have a lot of work to do.
So back to our story. Now we come to the
last thing that we know so far. We have
something called AI agents. So now we
are far beyond having a quick
conversation between the business user
and your model. Now the user is going to
ask for many stuff like for example how
many customers did left last year. So
what we can do we can have like one AI
agent that is using pre-trained model to
convert this text into an SQL query that
goes directly to the database and grab
the data and of course show it at the
end as visualizations. And another thing
the customer might ask for example where
I find the customer's data in which
system in which application. So for this
scenario we can use another AI agent
that could use as well pre-trained model
that's specialized on scanning
documents. So this time we don't need
the company's data we need the
documentations of the company. And now
if the customers ask something about the
future how many customers going to leave
next year then you can use an AI agent
that connects to our model that we
trained from the scratch that we are
very proud of. So if you look to this,
we're going to have a lot of AI agents
that are connecting to different models,
connecting to different data and
sources. So of course, we have to
orchestrate all those stuff and connect
everything. And that's why we're going
to have like a manager AI agent, the top
level agent that going to get the
prompts from the users and decide which
agents and models are involved and then
respond back to the users or do an
action like for example sending an
email. Well, that might be a lot of
informations for some of you. I can keep
going and adding stuff to this big
picture but it is [music] not fitting
anymore
to understand [music] what data
engineers does. We are not building
apps. We are not building softwares. We
are just building [music] data
pipelines. Pipeline that pulls the data,
clean it, transform it, load it and keep
running every day. Data engineering is
like the engine room behind every
datadriven company. You are the
engineer. You are the one that going to
go and move, transform and store massive
amount of data. So my friend that means
you are not building a shiny dashboard
or you are building front ends. You are
as a data engineer behind the scenes but
you go and expose the hidden complex
important data of the company and you
[music] bring it to a suitable platform
so that others can do smart things with
the data. Okay. So what is a data
pipeline? At a very high level a data
pipeline is just a flow. So data comes
in from the sources. They go through few
steps where we prepare them, clean them
and enhance them. And once they are
ready, we're going to load them into the
target table. So it is no rocket
science. As a data engineers, we have to
build only this the data pipeline. And
we use Python in order to do that. And
then other people going to start using
this prepared data in order to build
analytical use cases like a dashboard or
an AI and some machine learning stuff.
This is the big picture of pipeline. And
now we're going to zoom in into each
step in order to understand which Python
concepts are needed. So now let's start
with the first step on the left side.
The sources of our data could be in
different technologies like databases or
stored in files or maybe they are
provided as a stream like using Kafka
and they could live in APIs. So we have
different sources of our data. And now
the very first step in our pipeline is
extract and load. This is where
everything starts. So it is very simple.
We have to connect to the sources. start
reading the data and then loading it
into our system. So we are just taking
one copy of our data and putting it in
our system. No big smart thing, no
transformations. So now in order to do
this step in the pipeline, we write a
Python script. Okay, so that's all about
the first step. We didn't do something
smart. We just focus on how to get the
data in. Now the next step is all about
cleaning up the data and enhancing it.
So what we're going to do, we're going
to take this raw copy of the data that
is missing. We're going to start fixing
it, handling missing value, removing
duplicate, and doing small enhancements
on top of it. And of course, we're going
to do this step by writing as well a
Python main script. And as well, we're
going to have the same add-ons where
we're going to have a config file, a
logging, a data quality, and so on.
Okay. So now, so far what you have done,
the first step, we just brought the data
in. The second step, we just cleaned up
the data. And now moving on to the last
step inside our pipeline. Here we can
apply the business logic, and the fun
starts. So we're going to take the data
that is clean and start joining it
together doing some data aggregations
and start applying the business logic
the business data transformations. And
of course for this the same thing going
to happen. We're going to write main
Python scripts in order to do this step
and we're going to have on top of it
some add-ons like the config files, the
logging and the data quality. So as you
can see as data engineers our job is not
that hard. We just have to build this
data pipeline where it has mainly three
steps. The first one is extract and
load. So we're going to bring the data
from the sources into our system without
any extra logic or transformations. And
now the next step, we're going to take
the raw data and start cleaning it up
and enhance it. So we're going to fix
the data type. We're going to clean the
text. We're going to handle the dates
and make sure everything is prepared for
the last step where we going to
transform and apply the business logic.
So we're going to join the tables,
aggregate the data, apply the rules and
prepare a final product for the
analytics and as [music] well for AI use
cases.
In any [music] industry or business,
everyone at the top had the same
mission. Managers, stakeholders, project
leads all need to make smart decisions
and they need to make them fast. And
they ask question like which region is
failing behind, why profits are dropping
in the last month and where they should
put their money next. And those are
really critical business questions and
they need answers. So now if they try
without a good data, they are going to
guess. So they going to use opinions and
some gut feelings in order to answer
them. Deming said it best. Without data,
you are just another person with an
opinion. That's why most of the
companies they going to try to answer
the data using the company's data. And
for that the business going to hire a
data analyst in order to find the
answers from the data. But to do that
they need a tool. And if the company
doesn't have the right one, they usually
go and use spreadsheets like the Excel
files. So the analyst going to try to go
and collect the data from the sources
and put it in the Excel files. They're
going to clean up the data, fix mistakes
and prepare the data so that at the end
they going to present the answers using
numbers and charts to the managers and
after that the manager going to use them
in order to make critical business
decisions. So now this sounds like happy
ending, right? Everyone is happy and we
got the answers. But in real world, this
doesn't work like this. If you are using
spreadsheet or Excel to do data
analyszis, things can start to fall
apart. Let me show you what I mean. Now,
the entire process is manual. So, you
are connecting the sources, exporting
files, merging sheets, cleaning rows.
People think it is easy, but in reality,
this is painful and it takes a lot of
time. Sometimes [music] it take weeks
and I have seen cases where it takes
months. And if it takes a lot of time to
present the data, that means the data
inside the reports are actually old,
which means the managers are making
decisions based on old data and the
business might have been changed in the
last week and no one knows about it
because we have old data inside the
Excel files. So that means managers
makes decisions based on outdated data
and this might result to bad decisions
which going to cost the company a lot.
So the new generated data inside the
systems will not be automatically
updating the charts or whatever results
that you have in Excel. It's going to be
like snapshot static. Another issue is
that the company's systems are not
always like a simple database or files.
Now the systems lives in cloud. They
provide data in APIs or even they stream
their data in platforms like Kafka. and
pulling the data from those modern
systems into Excel by hand is almost
impossible. So you're going to struggle
with the modern technology. Another big
issue as well. The sources now are
generating massive amount of data. So if
you try to export everything to Excel
and put it in file at some point your
Excel file is going to explode and maybe
freeze or crashes. They simply can't
handle real big data. And another one
that can be funny to watch if the
company decide to speed up the process
by adding more people to the projects.
So you're going to have more than one
analyst that they going to try to
prepare this Excel file and guess what
[music] they cannot work inside the same
file at the same time. And the solution
for that each one going to go and create
their own copy. So that means you can
have multiple versions of the same file
and good luck merging all those stuff
back to one file. And another big issue
using Excel files is the security. So
the analysts or the managers might send
the Excel files through emails and those
files could be storing sensitive data
about the company and it is really easy
to hack the Excel files to get access to
them and could be easily end up in the
wrong hands. So your company's data are
totally unprotected if you put it
[music] in spreadsheets. And another
thing about the security, not all the
data inside the Excel should be
available for everyone in the company.
Sometimes part of the data is really
sensitive and only upper management in
the company are allowed to see it not
everyone in the company. So in Excel you
cannot go and apply something called
role level security to control which
department or which people are allowed
to see the data. So you're going to end
up creating multiple versions for
multiple departments. And now since we
are talking about departments we come to
the biggest issue the biggest
catastrophic. Different departments like
sales, finance, marketing have their own
analysts. So one analyst is exporting
the data, cleaning up and then they
build their own formulas and guess what
can happen if you leave it like this.
First people are spending their mornings
doing the same task and now if the
managers ask the same question to three
different analysts they going to get
three different answers. It's not
because they are wrong. It is because of
this whole system. One file is 2 weeks
old. Another one is 1 week old and
another just got updated yesterday. And
as well the calculation in each file
could be slightly different. So that
means my friends it is big confusion and
there is no more single point of truth
for the data. And my friends to be
honest I have seen this almost in every
company that I have joined. It is total
disaster and pure CHAOS
and that's why many of the companies
they understood they cannot rely on
spreadsheets to do data analyzes.
Instead they need a standard they need a
process platform to do the whole thing
in one place and we call this process
this system as a business intelligence
or as a shortcut BI. So what is that? A
business intelligence is the whole
process of working with data. So
collecting the data from the sources
cleaning up the data preparing and
organizing it and then turn it into
visuals so people can understand what is
going on and make better decisions. So
the BI the business intelligence is the
full workflow from start to finish. A
lot of people thinks business
intelligence is just like making charts
and dashboards. Well, it is way more
than that. And of course we need a tools
a platforms to do now the business
intelligence, right? And for that we
have two very famous platforms. We have
the Tableau and the Microsoft PowerBI.
And that's why you have it in the name
PowerBI BI business intelligence. That's
why we call PowerBI as a BI tool. Same
things goes of course for Tableau. Now
quickly what is the history of PowerBI?
Because PowerBI didn't start as a giant
platform. Everything began inside the
Excel. So Microsoft has tools like Power
Query and Power Bivot hidden inside
Excel. Those tools were very powerful.
But the thing is Excel itself was not
able to handle the big modern data. As I
showed you all the issues and problem of
the Excel and at the same time other
platforms like Tableau start to becoming
very popular because it offered a clear
way and easy way to do data
visualizations. So that's why Microsoft
understood they need something
completely new. They cannot keep adding
stuff to [music] Excel. They start
taking the strong parts of Excel and
turn them into new products focused on
data analyzers. And that's idea became
PowerBI in 2015. And since that point
until now, Microsoft keep [music]
pushing and keep improving the PowerBI
month after month. Better visuals, more
connectors, improving the performance,
deep integration of PowerBI with the
Microsoft ecosystem. And in the last
four years, they introduced the
Microsoft fabric and copilots in
PowerBI. So over the time PowerBI grew
into a full business intelligence
platform or a data analytics platform.
It became one of the Tableau's main
competitors. Both of them are now the
top tools in the world for BI. If you
have a look at Google Trends, you can
exactly see the clear shift. Tableau was
dominating for a long time. But PowerBI
kept growing and growing until we
reached the point where PowerBI get
served almost as much as Tableau
worldwide. So it is interesting where
PowerBI and Tableau are going to go over
the time and for PowerBI we have another
name we call it as data visualization
tool. So what is that? But first let's
have some cafe rights.
All right. So it is the process of
turning raw data and boring numbers into
visuals and charts like bar line pie
charts and heat maps just to make it
easier for human to understand the
complex raw data instantly because my
friends we are visual creatures. If you
see a picture of a tree you're going to
understand it right away. But if you
read the word tree your brain has first
to process it and turn it into visual.
So that means visuals skips this extra
steps which makes it easier for your
brain. So that means visuals are
processed way faster than reading a text
or looking to numbers. And not only
that, our brain remember them longer. So
we keep small part of what we hear, a
bit more of what we read, but most of
what we see. So this is the power of
visuals and data visualizations are very
powerful because you understand the
information faster. You see the patterns
and problems instantly. You can use them
to explain your ideas. You can tell a
story and with that the others can make
better decisions and everyone going to
remember the visuals way longer than
numbers. And exactly for that tools like
PowerBI focuses on data visualizations.
So now the question is what is inside
PowerBI and how it actually work. It is
[clears throat] divided into five
components and each one of them has its
own clear job. The first one is power
query. This is where you clean up your
data. You remove mistakes, duplicates,
you fix the formats. So it's all about
preparing the data. The second component
is the data module. Once everything is
cleared, it's time [music] to structure
and organize your data. So it's all
about how you go and connect your tables
to each others. And this is very
important to make everything accurate,
organized, and as well fast. Now moving
on to the next one, we have the DAX.
Everyone is afraid of this one. So DAX
is all about using calculations and math
in order to build the business logic
that you're going to need for the next
step. So everything so far is like
hidden. It's the background of the
PowerBI. No one sees it. And now it's
the first time you're going to build
something that the end user is going to
see the visuals. So here you're going to
build all those charts and big numbers,
tables and those filters and the dynamic
of everything just in order at the end
to tell a story using the data. Now once
everything is ready, you go to the last
component in order to share and publish
what you have built. So at the end
people going to view your report,
interact with it and make decisions. So
those are the five components and blocks
inside PowerBI that you have to use in
order to build something in PowerBI. So
it looks like a process a simple
pipeline. You bring the data in, you
clean it, you module it and organize it
then visualize it and at the end you
share it and you can do the whole thing
in just one platform the PowerBI. So now
let's talk about the PowerBI ecosystem
because PowerBI itself it is not just
one thing it is multiple things. So
Microsoft offers multiple tools and each
one of them has its own job. The first
one is the PowerBI desktop. This is the
app that you install locally on your PC
and I have bad news just to make it
clear you cannot install it on Mac
because it is Windows only unless you
are using some extra workarounds. So the
PowerBI desktop is where you spend most
of your time building things. It is
basically the engine of PowerBI.
Everything that you have talked about
inside this tool. The Power Query, the
data module, the DAX, the visuals, the
whole thing, the whole process is inside
this one tool. And everything, the data,
the modules, the reports going to be
stored into one single file locally at
your PC. And the extension of this file
going to be PVIX. And of course you can
go and share this file directly with the
others. But we don't want to have
another Excel's issue, right? We don't
do that. Instead of that, we're going to
publish everything that we have built to
a new tool to the next part of the
ecosystem, the PowerBI service. And at
this point, once you publish your report
from desktop to the service, your report
now going to live there. Now what going
to happen? your end users, your
consumers can open their browser and
start viewing your reports and
dashboards and interact with them. So
they can start filtering things,
checking the number and whatever they
need. And of course, if you have some
top managers that don't have the time to
open their laptops, no problem. This is
totally fine because they can go and
install the third tool, the PowerBI app
on their phone or tablet in order to
connect to the same reports that lives
in the cloud in the service. So using
their devices, they still can interact
with your report. Of course, there are a
lot of more extra stuff, but those are
the three major, let's say, tools that
Microsoft offers. A desktop where you
build things, the PowerBI service where
you're going to host and share your
reports, and this nice PowerBI app to
interact with your stuff using phone and
tablets. Now, you might ask, is PowerBI
only made for data analyst? Because we
have understood it is their main tool.
They use it in order to answer business
questions using data and visuals. So if
I am not data analyst, if I do something
else, should I learn PowerBI? Well, my
friend, of course. Like for example, me
as a data engineer who go and build data
pipelines, I still go and use PowerBI in
order to make dashboards to monitor my
system to check the data quality and
make sure that everything is loaded
correctly the way it should. So I use
PowerBI to monitor internally the whole
system that I'm building as a data
engineer. Now as well you can use it as
a data scientist. So you go and build
models, predictions and machine learning
solutions but still as a data scientist
you have to go and share your work with
non tech and business users and you
cannot share with them your code or
notebooks. You're going to go and use
PowerBI to share your work because it is
simple and easy for business users. So
it is the best way to explain the
complex things sets you do as a data
scientist. And of course if you are a
business analyst you're going to end up
as well using PowerBI. So you're going
to use it to answer what happens, why it
happened and what should happen next. So
you use insights for conversations and
discussions. And by the way, not only at
work, I know a lot of people that use
PowerBI for personal life at home. They
use it in order to track their spending,
for budgeting, for investments. Anytime
you have numbers and you would like to
make visuals, you can use PowerBI. So
for example, I use it for YouTube stuff
to analyze and track things. It just
works for everyone. And now my friends,
there is like an endless war about which
BI [music] tool is better, PowerBI or
Tableau. I saw this topic discussed
everywhere at YouTube, social media, and
at companies. There are endless content
and meeting and efforts about it. Now if
you ask me which one should I use or
which one is better I'm going to tell
you both are good and there is one of
the project that I have done that I
utilized both of them PowerBI and
Tableau at the same time. So now I'm
going to tell you a few reasons why some
teams tend to use PowerBI instead of
Tableau. The first and obvious reason is
it fits your daily tools. Most of people
at work already use Microsoft products
like Outlook, Teams, Excel, PowerPoint,
SharePoint and PowerBI feel natural
because it fits. It looks like Excel. It
looks like PowerPoint and it is already
connect to all those tools without any
extra steps. The second reason, it is
very easy to switch from Excel to
PowerBI because you already know DAX.
The interface looks like an Excel and
the charts and dashboards looks similar.
you have already the background to
switch to PowerBI. Reason number three,
it is more affordable. PowerBI cost less
than other tools and now my friend of
course all the companies are trying to
cut costs [music] and one of the major
cost in each budget is actually
licenses. This is a winning factor why
they utilize PowerBI and another reason
inside PowerBI you have a lot of things
like the data cleanup and preparation
using the power query. Many other
platforms like Tableau, they offer like
a second tool like Tableau prep in order
to prepare the data. But with the
PowerBI desktop, you have like
everything in one place which makes it
easier for you not to jump between like
tools to do the whole process. And
another reason why people tend to use
PowerBI is that Microsoft really focuses
on this tool. Like there is a new
release, new updates every single month,
new visuals, new features, new
connectors. The tool is really keep
growing very fast. And another reason
which is my favorite one the data
moduling inside PowerBI is really
strong. So there are a lot of features
and advanced stuff that you can do as
you are moduling the data. If you
compare to Tableau Tableau is really
limited on how you build the data model
which [music] is a clear win for PowerBI
because if you have a strong data model
you can make very flexible and fast
insight with the PowerBI. So those are
the reasons why we use PowerBI instead
of other tools like Tableau. But the
major reasons are again it is cheaper
than other tools. It is integrated
everywhere in the Microsoft ecosystem at
work. And the third one, come on, it
looks like a powerful Excel. Everyone is
familiar and use Excel. So the interface
of the PowerBI looks really familiar. So
those are my reasons why I think PowerBI
is becoming very popular and widely
used. Okay. So my friends, PowerBI is
great but actually not perfect. And
there are some scenarios where I'm going
to say PowerBI is limited compared to
the other tools like Tableau. Like the
biggest limitation with the PowerBI is
you cannot use it for very complex
visuals. Now if you are building
operational reports where you have some
basic charts, a bar line or pie charts,
some table and filter then PowerBI is
more than enough. But the thing is if
things get a little bit advanced and
complex like if you are a data scientist
that is making dot plots or some
advanced insights about the data it is
way easier to use Tableau and as well
faster. It's stills stronger and wins
here compared to PowerBI. And another
thing where I cannot use PowerBI is that
there are limitations. So if you are
using scatter charts in PowerBI, you are
limited only to show few thousands of
data points which is really a disaster
if you have a lot of data. You would
like even to show hundred of thousands
of data points in order to find those
outliers. And Tableau does not enforce
any hard limitations or restrictions on
the number of data points on the visual.
Literally I had one visual that is
showing millions of data points on my
dashboard in Tableau. And another reason
which is really annoying, you cannot run
PowerBI desktop for Mac users. You need
always to use workaround where tools
like Tableau you can install it in both
Windows and Mac. So those are the major
reasons let's say to not use PowerBI.
And this is exactly why I have utilized
in one project both the tools PowerBI
and Tableau. So for basic operation
reports and standard reports that goes
to managers and leaders I have utilized
PowerBI which is more than enough and I
can tell you 80% of requirements and
reports fits into those two categories
and only for complex and advanced
analytics that is usually prepared by
advanced data analyst and data
scientist. We use Tableau because it is
faster for big data and as well you can
create highly customized charts and of
course not everyone in the company did
use it. So we give it an access only for
like a focused audience that has
advanced analytical requirements. So
this is my take on why we use PowerBI
and when not to use it. All right
friends, so that was a whole full
introduction about what [music] is
PowerBI.
So what is exactly [music] SQL?
Everything generate data and data is
everywhere. Your first name is data,
your mobile and everything inside the
mobile is data. Car is as well
generating a lot of data. Bank, your
finance statements, everything is data.
And now of course the question is where
do we store our data? Personally, we
store a lot of our data in like Excels,
spreadsheets, in a text file. So you
store a lot of your data in different
files. Now how about companies? They
have a lot of things that generate a lot
of data that the products that they
produce their customers as well
generating a lot of data and sales
informations and a lot of things. So
companies generate massive amount of
data. So now the big question is how
they handle the data, how they store it.
Of course they cannot go and use like
simple files. They need something
bigger, stronger and smarter. And here
where the database comes in. So think
about the database. It's like a
container for storing data. But instead
of just dumping files into folders, the
database organized the data. So it is
easy to access, to manage and to search.
So a database simply it is a container
that stores data. So now you might ask
why we are using database. Can't we just
use files like I do it personally? Well,
let me tell you why we use databases.
Imagine that someone asks the following
question. Go and find the total spending
in your data. So now in order for Mike
to find the total spending and the costs
he will be opening each of those files
one by one searching for the costs
trying to combine the data and it's
going to be very long and messy process.
But now in the other side if your data
in database and you want to ask a
question it's going to be very easy. So
all what you have to do is to talk to
the database to ask a question and the
database can answer your question with a
result. And now comes of course the
question how do we talk to a database?
Well, we use SQL. SQL is the language
that you use in order to talk to the
database. It stands for structured query
language. SQL. And here you have people
that call it SQL like me and others that
call it SQL. There is no right and
wrong, but if you follow me through the
course, I think you will start saying
SQL. So, by using SQL, you can ask the
database, you can ask your data, and the
database going to answer your question
by sending you a result. So this process
is very easy, simple and fast. And this
is way better than having your data
stored in different files. Another
reason why we use databases is that they
can handle really huge amount of data.
So sometimes we have like millions of
data inside our database. But in the
other side, if you are storing your data
inside spreadsheets and you have like
massive amount of data, what can happen?
Your spreadsheets going to just break.
They simply can't handle big data. And
another reason why we use databases is
that it is just secure. It is safer to
store important and critical data inside
the database than just storing it in
spreadsheets and files. So the databases
are secure and you can control who is
accessing what. So it is just more
professional to store the data inside a
database. All right my friends so far
what we have learned most of the
companies stores their data inside a
container called a database and for you
in order to ask questions and to talk to
your database you have to speak the
language of SQL.
Now I'm going to show you how it looks
like usually in companies. So we have
our data inside the database and then
you will have multiple people with
multiple roles that are just writing
different SQLs in order to talk to the
data. But now not only employees and
people interact with the database. You
could build a website or an application
that as well interacts with the database
by sending different SQLs. And of course
depend on how many people are
interacting with the application and the
website it might generate really massive
amount of SQLs that sends to the
database. And not only that you might
has as well tools in order to do data
visualizations where you have like a
dashboard or reports maybe created using
PowerBI or Tableau and it is used by
stakeholders and managers in order to
make decisions and as well those tools
will be connected to the database and
creating SQLs. So now as you can see we
have a lot of interactions with the
database from people applications tools
a lot of things are generating SQLs and
interacting with the database but the
database is just a container and storage
right so we need something a software
that manage all those requests and
that's why we have something called
database management system DPMS so it is
a software that going to manage all
those different requests to our database
and it going to make the priority which
SQL must be executed First, this
software can as well manage the security
whether the SQL is allowed to be
executed in the first place. So my
friends, the DPMS is the software that
going to manage the database. And now we
are not done yet. There is something
missing. So we have our data, we have
the software. What is missing here is
the hardware. So in real companies, we
cannot run that on our PC because first
our PC is weak and as well it goes
offline. That's why we need a server.
server. It is like a very powerful PC
and as well it lives 24/7. So it is
always available and here we can decide
whether we're going to have a server
inside the company or we can use cloud
services in order to run our database.
So my friends so far what we have
learned the database it is container to
store the data. The SQL it is the
language in order to talk to the
database. The DPMS it is the manager it
manages the database and the server it
is the physical machine where the
database [music] lives. So this is how
it looks like.
And now my [music] friends there are
different types of databases. So let's
see what do we have. The first and the
most famous one it is the relational
database. It is very simple. It is like
spreadsheets call them table where we
have columns and rows and then there is
like a relationship between those tables
to describe how they relate to each
other and that's why we call it
relational database. So if people hear a
database they're going to think about
this one. Now we have another type of
database is called key value. This time
the data is organized completely
different where you have pairs of keys
and values. Think about it. It's like a
big dictionary where you have a word
like the key and the definition of the
word. This is the value. And now moving
on to the next one. This is as well
important column based. So now instead
of grouping the data by the rows, this
type of databases group the data into
columns. That's why it's called column
based. And this is very advanced
database in order to handle huge amount
of data where the main purpose is to
search for data. Moving on to another
database called graph database. The main
focus here is the relationship between
objects. So the main idea here is how to
connect my data points. And now finally
we have the document database. The data
is stored as entire documents where the
structure of the data is not that
important. What is more important is to
fit everything in one page in one
document. And now if you look to those
five types we can group the document
graph column based key value all those
databases called noSQL databases and the
relational database SQL database and in
this course we will be focusing of
course on the relational database and
I'm sure you have heard about like the
Microsoft SQL server the MySQL the
posris SQL all those databases they are
SQL relational database and for the key
value you have the radius the Amazon
Dynamo DB and we have for The column
based we have the Cassandra and the red
shift. For the graph database we have
the Neo4G and the very famous database
the MongoDB as a document database. Now
my friends for this course we're going
to be focusing on the SQL relational
databases because it is the most famous
one and the most used one in companies
and I will be focusing on the Microsoft
SQL server. So those are the different
types of databases. [music]
Now the databases are very structured
and organized. It has the following
hierarchy. The starting point is the
server as we learned it is powerful PC
and it is where the database lives and
inside it we can have multiple
databases. So maybe you have a database
for the sales and another one for the
HR. So the server can host multiple
databases. And as we learned a database
is a container of your data. Now moving
on to the next level. In each database
we can have multiple schemas. A schema
it is like category or you can call it a
logical container that we can use it in
order to group up related objects like
let's say you have hundred of tables. So
you can split all the tables that has to
do with the orders in one schema and
then another group of tables with the
schema customers and so on. So it help
you to organize your tables and your
objects in the database. And now if you
go inside schema you can have multiple
objects like tables. So now of course
the question is what is a table? It is
like spreadsheet. It organize your data
in two columns. The column define the
data that you store inside it. So you
have one column about the customer ID,
another column about the names, the
scores, the birthday. So each column is
about one type of data and sometimes we
call the columns as fields. Now the
other thing that we have in tables is
the rows or sometimes we call it
records. It is where actually the data
is stored. Now in this example, each
record represent one customer, one
person. So we have one record for Maria,
John and Peter. Thus we call them rows.
Now in each table there is like one very
important column called the primary key.
It is always very important to have like
one unique identifier for each customer
for each row. And we use it for
different purposes in order to combine
it with another table in order to
identify quickly one customer. So it is
unique. It's like fingerprint and there
is no two customers having the same ID.
Now the overlapping between the columns
and the rows we have a single value a
cell and each value each column stores
specific data type. A data type it is
like what kind of data we are storing
like an integer 1 2 30 or a decimal
where you have a decimal point 3.14. Now
if you want to store characters we have
different data types for that like you
want to store the name or the
description. So here we can use the char
or the vchar. So you store inside them
like the first name Maria or something.
Now you might ask what is a char or
vchar? So the char always a fixed one.
So if you define it like five characters
always it's going to go and reserve five
characters from the space. But if you
want things more dynamic then you go
with the vchar. And now moving on we
have another data types called the date
and time. So if you want to store a date
like the birth dates and if you want to
store the time information you can use
the time data type. So we call those
stuff intimol char date time they are
data types. So my friends as you can see
SQL databases are very organized and
structured. [music]
Okay. So now let's focus more about the
SQL itself. We have in SQL different
type of commands. So let's say that we
have a database and this database is
empty. So we have nothing inside it. Now
of course the first thing that you have
to do is to write an SQL with the
command create in order to create brand
new table in the database. So once you
execute it the database going to go and
build one. But this table is empty. So
we have nothing inside it. So now what
you have done here is you have defined
something new. Right? And we call this
type of commands the data definition
language. The DDL we have create to
create something new. Alter in order to
edit something that already exists and
drop in order to delete something to
drop for example a table. So this is the
first family of commands. Now if you
look at our table it is empty. What do
we need? We need data. So let's say that
we have a website or an application. Now
this application is generating a lot of
data. Now in order for this application
to move the data inside our new table,
it must use the SQL command insert. So
if you execute insert, you can add a new
data inside your table. This type of
commands we call it data manipulation
language. And here we have three
commands. Insert in order to insert a
new data, update in order to update an
already existing data, and delete in
order to go and delete data from your
table. And that's why we call it data
manipulation language because you are
manipulating your data. So what do we
have now? We have table. We have data
inside the table. Now what we can do? We
can start asking questions. So let's say
that you have analytical question about
your data. Now all what you have to do
is to write something called SQL query
and inside it you use the command select
but the whole thing we call it a query.
So you send a query to the database. you
have a question and the database can
return for you the result the data
answering your query your question and
we call this type of activities using
SQL the data query language and here we
have only one and it is very famous we
have the select we can use it in order
to query our data so those are the three
different commands in SQL and of course
we're going to learn all of them but we
will spend most of our time learning how
to write the correct query for the
correct answer.
And now you might ask me bar why we have
to learn SQL and if the time goes backs
are you going to learn SQL again? Well
for sure of course and here are the top
three reasons that I have. The first one
you have to learn it in order to talk to
the data. You know most of the companies
stores their data in databases and this
is a standard way. This is how they do
it. And if you want to work on the
company in the data field and you want
to talk to their data then you have to
use SQL. It's like you move to another
country where they speak another
language and you want to live there for
a long time, you have to speak the
language. The same thing here. If you
want to work with data, you have to
learn the language in order to speak to
the database, the SQL. So this is for me
the most important reason why we have to
learn SQL and SQL it is in high demand.
If you go now and check the job
description of the software developer,
data analyst, data engineer, data
scientist, I promise you, you will find
there that they going to demand for SQL.
So you will find they're going to ask
for SQL skills almost in each job
description. So if you check for any
data related jobs you will find that
they're going to ask for SQL skills. Now
another reason that I have is it is
industry standard. So if you go and
check multiple modern data platforms and
tools like PowerBI, Tableau, Kafka,
Spark, Synapse, you will understand that
there will be always a section where you
have to enter SQL code. So most of those
vendors adopt SQL because it is the
standard. It is widely used. It is like
selling points that their tools are
easy. So those are my top three reasons
why SQL is still relevant and why you
have to learn it. Okay my friends. So
with that we have now clear
understanding what is an SQL, why we
need it, what are databases and their
different types, why do we have DBMS,
servers and as well now you have
understanding how things are very
organized and structured inside the
databases. [music] So that's all this is
SQL.
Okay. So [music] now let's start with
basics. What is programming language? So
now imagine that you want to give your
computer a task and you say hey computer
calculate 5 + 5. Well your computer will
not understand what is exactly you're
talking about and nothing going to
happen. So we cannot use the natural
human language in order to give tasks
for your PC. So now instead with us we
have to give the instructions in a
language where the computer understand
it. We write a short piece of code like
for example here in Python print [music]
5 + 5. Now the computer going to
understand the instruction and give us
the result 10. So a program it is like
set of instructions that is written in a
language the computer can follow. But my
friend not all languages are the same.
Some are made for people and others are
made for machines. So now at the top we
have the natural language like you say
hey please calculate 5 + 5. And we have
a lot of natural languages. We have the
English, Spanish, Hindi. They are easy
for us but far too complex for computer
to understand. Now moving on. Then we
have the highlevel languages. So they
are programming languages [music] but
they are made for human because they are
very simplified, logical and really easy
to write and to read. And we have a lot
of languages like Python and JavaScript.
They are high-level languages. And now
next we are going lower. We are going to
the low-level languages. Programming
languages can talk directly to the
machines, but they are really hard for
humans. It's hard to read, to write, and
as well to understand. [music] And here
we have examples like the assembly and
the C language. And now at the very
bottom, we have the machine language.
And this one is made of binary code, a
combination of ones and zeros. [music]
And this is exactly what your computer
can understand, but it is impossible for
humans to read it, to understand it, to
write [music] it. So now if you look at
these levels each step down it going to
bring us closer on how the machine
thinks and each step up it going to
bring us closer on how human thinks. So
now if you're looking at Python the
highle language it is closer to the
natural language than the machine
language. So that means it is really
easy to learn and to write and it's like
an abstraction that hides the complexity
of low-level and machine languages. So
it's like a bridge between both worlds.
So this is exactly what are programming
languages and what [music] is Python.
Okay. So now I would like you to
understand [music] exactly how Python
works. So let's say you open your editor
and you start writing Python code and
usually we write the code inside a
Python file with the file extension of
py. [music] So here you are writing the
source code. Once you run your code, the
computer cannot immediately execute your
instructions because it is really high
level and the computer needs a lower
level of the code. So what happens?
There is something called compiler in
Python. It's going to take your Python
code and translate it to another code.
It's called the pyite [music] code with
the extension pyc python compiled. And
this can happen automatically and you
will not even notice it. So what
happened here? the compiler [music] of
Python going to translate the highlevel
language the Python code to a low-level
language [music] the bite code. So as
you can see it's really hard to
understand the bite code compared to the
Python code. So now our code is not yet
executed right Python [music] just did a
translation but now before anything to
be executed what can happen Python might
as well link some libraries. It is like
pre-written chunks of codes that helps
your code to do something specific like
working with files, handling data and so
on. Now Python has everything the bite
code the libraries and now Python can
run your bite code using something
called Python virtual machine. So it's
like a software that can understand the
bite code of Python and take care of
running it. So the Python virtual
machine going to finally converts your
instructions into machine codes once and
zero because this is the only thing that
your computer can really understand and
once it runs you will see at the results
whatever your program was designed to
do. And now all those three steps
compile, translate and execute we call
them the Python interpreter. So it's
like a toolbox that handles everything
needed to [music] run a Python code. So
again my friend you write Python code in
a high language then Python compiles it
and translate it into the byte code the
low language and then the virtual
machine going to take care of everything
going to take your bite code some
libraries and then it's going to run it
at your computer to see the results. So
this process happens every time you run
a Python code and everything is of
course automated [music]
and behind the scenes.
Okay. is now let's [music] talk about
why we should learn Python in the first
place. There are like too many
programming languages out there. So why
millions of people choose Python? So the
first and most important reason is
Python is very powerful and as well at
the same time very simple. You can build
really serious stuff with few line of
codes. So if you compare like Java and
Python in Java or C++ you can write like
a lot of lines in order to do a simple
task compared to Python where you need
only like one or two line. So as you can
see, Python is very simple compared to
other programming languages. Okay,
moving on to the second reason. Python
is used literally everywhere and you can
use it in order to build everything. So
you can use it to build websites, to
automate tasks, to work with data, to
build games and even control robots. So
whatever direction you want to go in
tech, you will find probably Python.
Okay, moving on to the next one. One of
the best things about Python is the
community. You are my friend, never
alone. There are thousands of developers
and experts like me sharing their
knowledge in tutorials or they are like
writing blog posts and as well
developing and sharing free libraries
opensource projects in GitHub and if you
are stuck or have any complex task I'm
sure there is like someone already
solved it and probably made a YouTube
video or a GitHub repo about it. So this
type of community makes the language
alive and when it comes to AI Python is
leading the way. Almost everything you
hear about today like Shajbt, image
generations, self-driving car models,
it's built with [music] Python because
Python has an incredible ecosystem for
AI and machine learning. So my friends,
this means the programming language of
AI is Python. And if you are interested
in the future, then Python is the right
language. And now because of all these
reasons, Python is one of [music] the
most in demand programming language in
the world right now. If you check any
job description in the tech world, you
will see everyone across all industries,
finance, healthcare, logistics, car
manufacturing, everyone is requesting
Python skill. So my friends, Python is
really easy to learn, has incredible use
cases. It is shaping the future with the
AI. It has huge community and it is
amazing for your career. So this is
exactly why millions learns [music] and
works with Python.
Okay. So [music] now I hope that I got
you motivated to learn Python and I will
not leave you there. I'm going to show
you now how to learn Python. So Python
is like a journey and every journey
needs a road map. So now everyone
everybody going to start from the same
place. Every expert, a data engineer,
AI, web, gaming developers, everyone has
to start at the same place. Everyone has
to learn how to write a simple code,
understand variables, how to work
[music] with data types, how to control
the flow of your codes and as well you
have to learn about the functions and
how to organize your code into small
reusable blocks. So this stage builds
your foundation and now after that
everyone has to go to the intermediate
level. Now we're going to level things
up. You're going to start learning how
to handle errors and exceptions, how to
structure your code using the OOP,
object-oriented programming, how to
split your projects into modules, and
how to work with files and many other
stuff. So at this phase, you start
feeling how your code is getting more
professional, more like a real
developer. So things going to make more
sense here. And now after that, everyone
going to start moving to the advanced
level. And here you can start learning
advanced techniques. We're going to go
outside of our code in order to connect
ourself with APIs in [music] order to
grab data from the internets and we're
going to learn stuff like how to test
your codes and how to scrap website to
collect data automatically and at this
level you're going to start doing real
projects and solving real problems. So
now as you can see all those three
levels they are the core of Python and
everyone must learn these techniques
because everyone need those techniques
in whatever you are building in the
future. And now after that of course we
cannot keep learning everything. It's
going to be really impossible. So you
have to really make thoughts about which
path you want to follow the direction
that match your interest and your career
goals. So you have to pick your path and
there are like a lot of options like for
example you could be a data engineer. If
you'd like to work with pipelines,
automations, moving data around then you
have to learn something like sparkl
processes and automations with python.
[music] Another path you can use Python
for data science if you enjoy working
with data charts insights. If yes then
you're going to be working with
libraries like pandas numpy and plotty
in order to analyze and visual your
data. If you want to go deeper and build
smart systems and models then you have
to work with Python libraries like
pytorch transformers and tensorflow and
another option and path you could use
python for web development. So if you
want to build websites and web apps then
you can use Python libraries and
frameworks like Flask, Django and
requests. And of course not only those
four we have a lot of other options like
using Python for game development. But
as you can see at the expert level at
the right side going to be almost
impossible to learn all those libraries.
So now if I look to this and tell you
about my journey. So I learned
everything in Python about data
engineering and then with the time I
start picking few libraries from the
other options like from the data science
I learned the plotty and the pandas and
from the AI and machine learning the
transformers. So I'm going to recommend
you to pick first a path make yourself
an expert there and with the [music]
time start exploring the other stuff.
So if you are new [music] to git don't
worry about it. It is simpler than it
sounds. So it's all about to have a safe
place where you can put your codes that
you are developing and you will have the
possibility to track everything happens
to the codes and as well you can use it
in order to collaborate with your team
and if [music] something goes wrong you
can always roll back.
Now designing [music] the data
architecture it is exactly like building
a house. So before construction starts,
an architect's going to go and design a
plan, a blueprint for the house. How the
rooms will be connected, how to make the
house functional, safe and wonderful.
And without this blueprint from the
architects, the builders might create
something unstable, inefficient or maybe
unlivable. The same goes for data
projects. A data architect is like a
house architecture. They design how your
data will flow, integrate and be
accessed. So as data architects we make
sure that the data warehouse is not only
functioning but also scalable and easy
to maintain. And this is exactly what we
will do now. We will play the role of
the data architect and we will start
brainstorming and designing the
architecture of the data warehouse. So
now I'm going to show you a sketch in
order to understand what are the
different approaches in order to design
a data architecture. And this phase of
the projects usually is very exciting
for me because this is my main role in
data projects. I am a data architect and
I discuss a lot of different projects
where we try to find out the best design
for the projects. All right. So now
let's go. Now the first step of building
a data architecture is to make a very
important decision to choose between
four major types. The first approach is
to build a data warehouse. It is very
suitable if you have only structured
data and your business want to build
solid foundations for reporting and
business intelligence. And another
approach is to build a data leak. This
one is way more flexible than a data
warehouse where you can store not only
structured data but as well semi and
unstructured data. We usually use this
approach if you have mixed types of data
like database tables, logs, images,
videos and your business want to focus
not only on reporting but as well on
advanced analytics or machine learning
but it's not that organized like a data
warehouse and data leaks. If it's too
much unorganized and turns into data
swamp and this is where we need the next
approach. So the next one we can go and
build data lake house. So it is like a
mix between data warehouse and data
lake. You get the flexibility of having
different types of data from the data
lake but you still want to structure and
organize your data like we do in the
data warehouse. So you mix those two
words into one. And this is a very
modern way on how to build that
architecture and this is currently my
favorite way of building data management
system. Now the last and very recent
approach is to build data mesh. So this
is a little bit different. Instead of
having centralized data management
system, the idea now in the data mesh is
to make it decentralized. You cannot
have like one centralized data
management system because always if you
say centralized then it means
bottleneck. So instead you have multiple
departments and multiple domains where
each one of them is building a data
product and sharing it with others. So
now you have to go and pick one of those
approaches. And in this project we will
be focusing on the data warehouse. So
now the question is how to build the
data warehouse. Well there is as well
four different approaches on how to
build it. The first one is the inmon
approach. So again you have your sources
and the first layer you start with the
staging where the row data is landing
and then the next layer you organize
your data in something called enterprise
data warehouse where you go and model
the data using the third normal format.
It's about like how to structure and
normalize your tables. So you are
building a new integrated data model
from the multiple sources. And then we
go to the third layer. It's called the
data marts where you go and take like
small subset of the data warehouse and
you design it in a way that is ready to
be consumed from reporting and it focus
on only one topic like for example the
customers sales or products and after
that you go and connect your BI tool
like PowerBI or Tableau to the data
march. So with that you have three
layers to prepare the data before
reporting. Now moving on to the next one
we have the Kimple approach. He says you
know what building this enterprise data
warehouse it is wasting a lot of time.
So what we can do we can jump
immediately from the stage layer to the
final data ms because building this
enterprise data warehouse it is a big
struggle and usually waste a lot of
time. So he always want you to focus and
building the data ms quickly as
possible. So it is faster approach than
inmon but with the time you might get
chaos in the data ms because you are not
always focusing in the big picture and
you might be repeating same
transformations and integrations in
different data ms. So there is like
trade-off between the speed and
consistent data warehouse. Now moving on
to the third approach we have the data
vault. So we still have the stage and
the data marts but it says we still need
this central data warehouse in the
middle but this middle layer we're going
to bring more standards and rules. So it
tells you to split this middle layer
into two layers the row vault and the
business vault. In the row vault you
have the original data but in the
business vault you have all the business
rules and transformations that prepares
the data for the data march. So data
vault it is very similar to the inmon
but it brings more standards and rules
to the middle layer. Now I'm going to go
and add a fourth one that I'm going to
call it medallion architecture and this
one is my favorite one because it is
very easy to understand and to build. So
it says you're going to go and build
three layers bronze, silver and gold.
The bronze layer it is very similar to
the stage but we have understood with
the time that the stage layer is very
important because having the original
data as it is it going to helps a lot by
traceability and finding issues. Then
the next layer we have the silver layer.
It is where we do transformations data
cleansing but we don't apply yet any
business rules. Now moving on to the
last layer the gold layer. It is as well
very similar to the data marts but there
we can build different type of objects
not only for reporting but as well for
machine learning for AI and for many
different purposes. So they are like
business ready objects that you want to
share as a data products. So those are
the four approaches that you can use in
order to build a data warehouse. So
again if you are building a data
architecture you have to specify [music]
which approach you want to follow.
What is exactly data [music] warehouse?
Why the companies try to build such a
data management system? So now the
question is what is a data warehouse? I
will just use the definition of the
father of the data warehouse bill in
one. A data warehouse is
subject-oriented integrated time variant
and nonvolatile collection of data
designed to support the management's
decision-m process. Okay, I I know that
might be confusing. Subject-oriented. It
means that a warehouse is always focused
on a business area like the sales,
customers, finance and so on. Integrated
because it goes and integrate multiple
source systems. Usually you build a
warehouse not only for one source but
for multiple sources. Time variance it
means you can keep historical data
inside the data warehouse. Nonvolatile
it means once the data enter the data
warehouse it is not deleted or modified.
So this is how build and modified data
warehouse. Okay. Okay, I'm going to show
you the scenario where your company
don't have a real data management. So
now let's say that you have one system
and you have like one data analyst has
to go to this system and start
collecting and extracting the data and
then he going to spend days and
sometimes weeks transforming the raw
data into something meaningful. Then
once they have the reports they're going
to go and share it. And this data
analyst is sharing the report using an
Excel. And then you have like another
source of data and you have another data
analyst that she is doing maybe the same
steps collecting the data spending a lot
of time transforming the data and then
share at the end like a report and this
time she is sharing the data using
PowerPoint and a third system and the
same story but this time he is sharing
the data using maybe PowerBI. So now if
the company works like this then there
is a lot of issues. First this process
it take two way long. I saw a lot of
scenarios where sometimes it takes weeks
and even months until the employee
manually generating those reports. And
of course, what can happen for the
users? They are consuming multiple
reports with multiple state of the data.
One report is 40 days old, another one
10 days and a third one is like 5 days.
So it's going to be really hard to make
a real decision based on this structure.
A manual process is always slow and
stressful and the more employees you
involved in the process the more you
open the door for human errors and
errors of course in reports leads to bad
decisions and another issue of course is
handling the big data. If one of your
sources generating like massive amount
of data then the data analyst going to
struggle collecting the data and maybe
in some scenarios it will not be anymore
possible to get the data. So the whole
process kind of breaks and you cannot
generate anymore fresh data for specific
reports. And one last very big issue
with that. If one of your stakeholders
asks for an integrated report from
multiple sources, well good luck with
that because merging all those data
manually is very chaotic, timeconuming
and full of risk. So this is just a
picture. If a company is working without
a proper data management, without a data
leak, data warehouse, data lake houses.
So in order to make real and good
decisions, you need data management. So
now let's talk about the scenario of a
data warehouse. So the first thing
that's going to happen is that you will
not have your data team collecting
manually the data. You're going to have
a very important component called ETL.
ETL stands for extract, transform, and
load. It is a process that you do in
order to extract the data from the
sources and then apply multiple
transformations on those sources and at
the end it loads the data to the data
warehouse and this one can be the single
point of truth for analyzes and
reporting and it is called data
warehouse. So now what can happen all
your reports going to be consuming this
single point of truth. So with that you
create your multiple reports and as well
you can create integrated reports from
multiple sources not only from one
single source. So now by looking to the
right side it looks already organized
right and the whole process is
completely automated. There is no more
manual steps which of course it reduces
the human error and as well it is pretty
fast. So usually you can load the data
from the sources until the reports in
matter of hours or sometimes in minutes.
So there is no need to wait like weeks
and months in order to refresh anything.
And of course the big advantage is that
the data warehouse itself it is
completely integrated. So that means it
goes and bring all those sources
together in one place which makes it
really easier for reporting and not only
integrated you can build in the data
warehouse as well history. So we have
now the possibility to access historical
data and what is also amazing that all
those reports having the same data
status. So all those reports can have
the same status maybe sometimes one day
old or something. And of course if you
have a modern data warehouse in cloud
platforms you can really easily handle
any big data sources. So no need to
panic if one of your sources is
delivering massive amount of data. And
of course in order to build the data
warehouse you need different types of
developers. So usually the one that
builds the ETL component and the data
warehouse is the data engineer. So they
are the one that is accessing the
sources, scripting the ATLs and building
the database for the data warehouse. And
now for the other part, the one that is
responsible for that is the data
analyst. They are the one that is
consuming the data warehouse, building
different data models and reports and
sharing it with the stakeholders. So
they are usually contacting the
stakeholders, understanding the
requirements and building multiple
reports based on the data warehouse. So
now if you have a look to those two
scenarios, this is exactly why we need
data management. [music]
Your data team is not wasting time and
fighting with the data. They are now
more organized and more focused and with
like a data warehouse and you are
delivering professional and fresh
reports that your company can count on
in order to make good [music] and fast
decisions. So this is why you need a
data management like a data warehouse.
Think about data warehouse as a busy
restaurant. Every day different
suppliers bring in fresh ingredients,
vegetables, spices, meat, you name it.
They don't just use it immediately and
throw everything in one pot, right? They
clean it, shop it, and organize
everything and store each ingredients in
the right place, fridge or freezer. So,
this is the preparing phase. And when
the order comes in, they quickly grab
the prepared ingredients and create a
perfect dish and then serve it to the
customers of the restaurant. And this
process is exactly like the data
warehouse process. It is like the
kitchen where the raw ingredients your
data are cleaned, sorted and stored. And
when you need a report or analyzes, it
is ready to [music] serve up exactly
like what you need.
What is [music] exactly an ETL? So our
data exist in a source system and now
what we want to do is is to get our data
from the source and move it to the
target. Source and target could be like
database tables. So now the first step
that we have to do is to specify which
data we have to load from the source. Of
course we can say that we want to load
everything. But let's say that we are
doing incremental load. So we're going
to go and specify a subset of the data
from the source in order to prepare it
and load it later to the target. So this
step in the ATL process we call it
extract. We are just identifying the
data that we need. We pull it out and we
don't change here anything. It's going
to be like one to one like the source
system. So the extract has only one task
to identify the data that we have to
pull out from the source and to not
change anything. So we will not
manipulate the data at all. It can stay
as it is. So this is the first step in
the ETL process, the extract. Now moving
on to the stage number two. We're going
to take this extract data and we will do
some manipulations, transformations and
we're going to change the shape of those
data. And this process is really heavy
working. We can do a lot of stuff like
data cleansing, data integration and a
lot of formatting and data
normalizations. So a lot of stuff we can
do in this step. So this is the second
step in the ETL process. The
transformation we're going to take the
original data and reshape it, transform
it into exactly the format that we need
into a new format and shapes that we
need for analyzes and reporting. Now
finally we get to the last step in the
ATL process. We have the load. So in
this step we're going to take this new
data and we're going to insert it into
the target. So it is very simple. We're
going to take this prepared data from
the transformation step and we're going
to move it into its final destination
the target like for example data
warehouse. So that's ETL in a nutshell.
First extract the row data then
transform it into something meaningful
and finally load it to a target where
it's going to make a difference. So
that's it. This is what we mean with the
ETL process. Now in real projects we
don't have like only source and targets
our data architecture going to have like
multiple layers depend on your design
whether you are building a warehouse or
a data lake or a data warehouse and
usually there are like different ways on
how to load the data between all those
layers and in order now to load the data
from one layer to another one there are
like multiple ways on how to use the ATL
process. So usually if you are loading
the data from the source to the layer
number one like only extract the data
from the source and load it directly to
the layer number one without doing any
transformations because I want to see
the data as it is in the first layer.
And now between the layer number one and
the layer number two you might go and
use the full ETL. So we're going to
extract from the layer one transform it
and then load it to the layer number
two. So with that we are using the whole
process the ETL. And now between layer
two and layer three we can do only
transformation and then load. [music] So
we don't have to deal with how to
extract the data because it is maybe
using the same technology. And we are
taking all data from layer 2 to layer
three. So we transform the whole layer 2
and then load it to layer three. And now
between three and four you can use only
the elm. So maybe it's something like
duplicating and replicating the data and
then you are doing the transformation.
So you load to the new layer and then
transform it. Of course, this is not a
real scenario. I'm just showing you that
in order to move from source to a
target, you don't have always to use a
complete ETL. Depend on the design of
your data architecture, you might use
only few components from the ETL. Okay.
So, this is how ETL [music] looks like
in real projects.
[music]
So, what is exactly data modeling?
Usually the source system going to
deliver for you row data unorganized,
messy, not very useful in its current
states. But now the data modeling is the
process of taking this row data and then
organize it and structure it in
meaningful way. So what we are doing we
are putting the data in new friendly and
easy to understand objects like
customers, orders, products. Each one of
them is focused on specific information
and what is very important is we're
going to describe the relationship
between those objects. So by connecting
them using lines. So what we have built
on the right side we call it logical
data model. If you compare to the left
side you can see the data model makes it
really easy to understand our data and
the relationship the processes behind
them. Now in data modeling we have three
different stages or let's say three
different ways on how to draw a data
model. The first stage is the conceptual
data model. Here the focus is only on
the entity. So we [music] have
customers, orders, products and we don't
go in details at all. So we don't
specify any columns or attributes inside
those boxes. We just want to focus what
are the entities that we have and as
well the relationship between them. So
the conceptual data model don't focus at
all on the details. It just gives the
big picture. So the second data model
that we can build is the logical data
model. And here we start specifying what
are the different columns that we can
find in each entity like we have the
customer ID, the first name, last name
and so on. And we still draw the
relationship between those entities and
as well we make it clear which columns
are the primary key and so on. So as you
can see we have here more details but
one thing we don't describe a lot of
details for each column and we are not
worry how exactly we going to store
those tables in the database. The third
and last stage we have the physical data
model. This is where everything gets
ready before creating it in the
database. So here you have to add all
the technical details like adding for
each column the data types and the
length of each data type and many other
database techniques and details. So
again if you look to the conceptual data
model it gives us the big picture and in
the logical data model we dive into
details of what data we need and the
physical layer model prepares everything
for the implementation in the database.
And to be honest in my projects I only
draw the conceptual and the logical data
model because drawing and building the
physical data model needs a lot of
efforts and time and there are many
tools like in data bricks they
automatically generate those models. So
in this project what we're going to do
we're going to draw the logical data
model for the gold layer.
All right. It's now for analytics and
especially for data warehousing and
business intelligence. We need a special
data model that is optimized for
reporting and analytics and it should be
flexible, scalable and as well easy to
understand. And for that we have two
special data models. The first type of
data model we have the star schema. It
has a central fact table in the middle
and surrounded by dimensions. The fact
table contains transactions, events, and
the dimensions contains descriptive
informations. And the relationship
between the fact table in the middle and
the dimensions around it forms like a
star shape. And that's why we call it
star schema. And we have another data
model called snowflake schema. It looks
very similar to the star schema. So we
have again the fact in the middle and
surrounded by dimensions. But the big
difference is that we break the
dimensions into smaller subdimensions.
And the shape of this data model as you
are extending the dimensions it's going
to looks like a snowflake. So now if you
compare them side by side you can see
that the star schema looks easier right?
So it is usually easy to understand easy
to query. It is really perfect for
analyzers but it has one issue with
that. The dimension might contain
duplicates and your dimensions get
bigger with the time. Now if you compare
to the snowflake you can see the schema
is more complex. You saw you need a lot
of knowledge and efforts in order to
query something from the snowflake. But
the main advantage here comes with the
normalization as you are breaking those
redundancies in small tables. You can
optimize the storage but to be honest
who care about the storage. So for this
project I have choose to use the star
schema because it is very commonly used
perfect for reporting like for example
if you're using PowerBI and we don't
have to worry about the storage. So
that's why we're going to adopt this
model to build our gold layer.
Okay. So now one more thing about those
data models is that they contain two
types of tables fact and dimensions.
[music]
So when I say this is a fact table or a
dimension table well the dimension
contains descriptive informations or
like categories that [music] gives some
context to your data. For example a
product info you have product name
category subcategories and so on. This
is like a table that is describing the
products [music] and this we call it
dimension. But in the other hand we have
facts. They are events like
transactions. They contain three
important informations. First you have
multiple ids from multiple dimensions.
Then we have like date informations like
when the transaction or the event did
happen. And the third type of
information you're going to have like
measures and numbers. So if you see
those three types of data in one table,
then this is effect. So if you have a
table that answers how much or how many,
then this is effect. But if you have a
table that answers who, what, where,
then this is a dimension table. [music]
So this is what dimension and fact
tables.
[music] All right, my friends. So we're
going to start with a secret, a little
trick that I usually do by analyzing any
data sets. So let's start with a little
coffee before [music] we start. H, this
is really hot. Okay. So the secret says
as I'm looking to any data sets in any
projects I see the data always divided
between dimensions and measures.
>> What truth?
>> You take the blue pill, you take the red
pill. All I'm offering is the truth.
Nothing more.
If you see your data like me as
dimensions and measures, you can
generate like endless amount of insights
from any projects from any data sets and
you will find me through the projects
that I'm always speaking about measures
and dimensions. So I'm going to show you
how I usually do it. So now usually by
looking to any data set in any project.
So you have like multiple columns and
rows. Here I see the data always
splitted into two categories either a
dimension or a measure. And now of
course the question is here is my column
a dimension or a measure? Well in order
to assign it to one of those categories
you have to ask the first question is it
a numeric value? If it's not so you have
like string or date or any other data
type then it is a dimension and if it is
yes a numeric then you have to ask the
second question does it make sense to
aggregate it. So if the answer for both
questions is yes, it is numeric and it
makes sense to aggregate it then it is a
measure otherwise it is a dimension. Now
let's practice and have some examples.
So now by looking to the values of the
column category you can see all the
values are characters so it is not
numeric that means this column is a
dimension. So it is very simple. Let's
take another column. We have the sales
amount. So now as you can see the values
are numeric and as well it makes sense
to aggregate those values. we can get
the total sales or the average sales and
so on. So it fulfill both of the
conditions. It is numeric and it makes
sense to aggregate it. That's why we say
sales is a measure. Now if you're
checking the values of the product name,
you can see that all of them are
characters and names. So it is not
numeric. That means the product is a
dimension. Moving on to the next one, we
have the quantity. The values are
numeric and as well it makes sense to
aggregate it. Can summarize all those
values to have the total quantity. So
quantity is a measure. Now if you are
looking to the values of the birth dates
you can see this is a date information
it is not numeric so that means it is a
dimension right but if you calculate the
age from the birth dates age of the
customer going to be in numeric and it
makes sense to aggregate it for example
finding the average age of customers. So
if we derive a numeric value from a
dimension then we can use [music] it as
a measure. So age is a measure and now
we come to something really tricky. This
is the ID. So for example, if you are
checking the customer ID, you can see
all those values are numeric. So the
first condition is fulfilled. Now the
very important question does it make
sense to aggregate the ids? Well, those
ids are unique identifier for a customer
and if you find like the average of that
it is not like helpful, right? I cannot
think of one use case of aggregating the
customer ID like having the average of
all those ids or summarizing the ids. So
it makes no sense to aggregate it.
That's why we can consider the ID of a
customer as a dimension not as a
measure. So as you can see it is very
simple. If it is numeric and it makes
sense to aggregate then it is measure
otherwise it is a dimension. And this is
the foundations of any data analytics.
If you see your data as dimensions and
measures you can generate a lot of use
cases and insights from your data sets.
Now I totally understand if you are
still confused about dimensions and
measures and you might be asking why do
I need measures and dimensions. Well, if
you are doing any type of data analysis
or you are exploring any data sets, you
will be end up always like grouping up
the data by something like you are
grouping the data by countries or
grouping the data by for example
products or categories. So we need
dimensions to group up our data and in
the other sides you will be asking
questions like how much, how many, what
is the total of something. So you always
need to aggregate or calculate something
right and for that you need the measure.
So we need the measures in order to
answer the question how many and how
much and we need the dimensions in order
to group up the data by something. So
that's why almost in any type of data
analyzes you need dimensions and
measures and this can be [music] more
clear as we progress in the projects.
I [music] want to tell you a secret
principle concept that each data
architect must know and that is the
separation of concerns. So what is that?
As you are designing an architecture,
you have to make sure to break down the
complex system into smaller independent
parts and each part is responsible for a
specific task. And here comes the magic.
The component of your architecture must
not be duplicated. So you cannot have
two parts are doing the same thing. So
the idea here is to not mix everything
and this is one of the biggest mistakes
in any big projects and I have shown
that almost everywhere. So a good data
architects follow this concept this
principle. So for example if you are
looking to our data architecture we have
already done that. So we have defined
unique set of tasks for each layer. So
for example we have said in the silver
layer we do data cleansing but in the
gold layer we do business
transformations and with that you will
not be allowing to do any business
transformations in the silver layer and
the same thing goes for the gold layer.
You don't do in the gold layer any data
cleansing. So each layer has its own
unique tasks and the same thing goes for
the bronze layer and the silver layer.
You do not allow to load data from the
source systems directly to the silver
layer because we have decided the
landing layer. The first layer is the
bronze layer otherwise you will have
like set of source systems that are
loaded first to the bronze layer and
another set is skipping the layer and
going to the silver. And with that we
have overlapping you are doing data
ingestion in two different layers. So my
friends if you have this mindsets
separation of concerns I [music] promise
you you're going to be a top data
architect.
All right, great. So with that we
[music] have a data model and we can say
we have something called a data products
and we will be sharing this data product
with different type of users and there
is something that every data products
absolutely needs and that is [music] the
data catalog. It is a document that can
describe everything about your data
model. columns, the tables, maybe the
relationship between the tables as well.
And with that, you make your data
product clear for everyone. And it's
going to be for them way easier to
derive more insights and reports from
your data product. And what is the most
important one? It is time-saving because
if you don't do that, what can happen?
Each consumer, each user of your data
product will keep asking you the same
questions about what do you mean with
this column? What is this table? How to
connect the table A with the table P?
and you will keep repeating yourself and
explaining stuff. So instead of that you
prepare a data catalog, a data model and
you deliver everything together to the
users and with that you are saving a lot
of time and stress. I know it is
annoying to create a data catalog but it
is investments [music] and best
practices.
So let's keep it simple. An AI engineer
is someone that builds [music]
systems that use AI to solve real
business problems. So that means you are
not building a shad GBT or you are not
training a data model. You are building
[music] an AI system. So what is inside
an AI system? You're going to find the
following components. You will be
connecting AI models like the open AI
models from hugging face. You will be
connecting the company's data,
databases, files, documents and you will
be connecting as well the company's
tools and apps like emails, some
internal services and stuff and
interfaces where the user going to
interact with the AI system. So as you
can see you are just connecting stuff in
one place and your main job is to make
everything correct, secure, [music]
fast, scalable and cost efficient.
>> [music]
>> Prompt engineering. Most people think
prompt engineering is just like you are
typing something into Shajib and hoping
for a good answer. But there is actually
a skill behind it. And it's all about
how you communicate with a model so it
[music] understand exactly what you want
and how to get a tailored answer exactly
how you expect. So that means you're
going to give a detailed and clear
instructions and context. [music] You're
going to tell the model who it is and
what its role and show examples of the
results that you want. Each time you get
an answer from the AI, you're going to
review it and [music] improve your
prompts step by step.
Open AAI API. So the API going to let
you interact with the same model but
with one big difference inside your own
app, inside your website, your products.
So with that you are building like a
chatbot assistance inside your tools and
it is very simple to do. It's just few
lines of Python. [music] You send a
prompt, you get a response and you're
going to display it wherever you want.
So
as you are building your AI systems,
you're going to notice that you cannot
rely completely on OpenAI because
actually they are closed source. That
means you have no control over the
model. You cannot see how exactly it
works. You're going to pay a lot for
using tokens every time and if you are
not using Azure your company data going
to leave your environment and this is a
huge problem for many businesses. So
this is where the hacking phase comes
into the picture. It is the biggest
community library for AI models. There
are already more than 2 million models
over there and the best thing most of
them are for free. That means you can go
and find a model for almost any problem
that you might encounter. And my friend,
this is exactly why I keep repeating the
same thing. As a data science in
industry, we don't have anymore to train
anything from the scratch. All what you
have to do is just to find the right
model for your business case and just
fine-tune it. And the big advantage with
the hugging face is that you can
download the models locally at your
machine and you can deploy it anywhere
you want. With that you stay in control.
You can use sensitive data for the model
because nothing is leaving your
environment and as well you reduce the
[music] costs.
So now let's say that you can talk to AI
models, you can write really good
prompts, you can build really cool
demos, but this is not enough to build
an AI system because you need to connect
everything together. And this is where
Langshain comes in. So you can use
langin in order to orchestrate the whole
process to connect all the models that
you need the tools the memory and as
well to build your business logic. So
the AI can take multiple steps in order
to complete a full task. And this is
exactly what AI system does. It's not
just like one prompt and [music] one
answer.
[music] We going to learn about rag
retrieval augmented generation. The
issue is that all the AI models are
actually pre-trained using public data.
[music] But of course, the company's
data are protected and not available
publicly, which means AI models has no
idea about your company's data. So we
have somehow to connect the company's
data to the AI model. And here comes the
concept of rag. So here how it works.
First you take all the company's data,
PDFs and files and you want to store
them into something called Victor
database. So all what you have to do is
to turn a text into something fancy
called embedding. It is just
representing your text with numbers and
then load and store all those embeddings
inside the Victor database. So once a
user ask a question it going to turn
into embedding and the system going to
start comparing and searching for the
closest match using semantic search. So
once it finds the right information the
LLM model going to turn it into
response. So it's all about adding a
memory to the LLM model to use your real
data instead of relying on what they
were trained on.
We all used AI [music] chatbots like the
Shajbet. You write a prompt and it gives
you back a text. But of course, this is
not enough. Companies want more than a
nice answer on the screen. They want an
AI that actually gets the works done.
And this is exactly why we have AI
agents. An agent does first the thinking
and then it going to take a real action.
like for example maybe talking to a
database, updating records, calling an
API and maybe triggering a workflow and
as well it is great in order to automate
a lot of boring task that we do normally
at the work like reading the incoming
emails and responding to it creating a
summary of a meeting and as well
creating those boring Jira and Service
Now tickets. So it is way more than just
a chat with AI. It is an AI that is
actually [music] doing a work.
The MCP model context protocol. Now AI
agents can only take real actions like
checking emails, querying a database or
calling an API only if they are
connected to the external sources. And
here my friend, there are like two big
problems. First, if you connect your AI
agents directly to the productive
database, this is really risky. And the
second issue, we have a lot of external
systems and you're going to end up
writing and building connectors for each
tool. And this takes a lot of time and
efforts in order to create a new
connectors each time you are connecting
a new system to the AI agents. [music]
And this is exactly why we have MCB. It
fixed those issues. We're going to add a
safe and standard layer between your AI
agents and your sources. And this has my
friend a lot of benefits. First of all,
you can plug and play any system to your
AI agents without creating each time a
new connectors using this layer going to
give you a full control on how the AI
going to interact with your sources
where you can add a lot of policies in
order to protect your external sources.
So using MCB servers and protocols, it
going to makes everything like faster.
You can connect a lot of things and as
well you're going to feel safe
connecting AI agents to your sources. If
you like this type of content where I'm
sketching stuff and I'm showing you all
things behind the scenes, then support
my work by subscribing, liking, and
commenting and sharing it with other
people like you. And you can check my
website for the other courses like the
SQL and Tableau. You can follow my
written content in my newsletter and
LinkedIn. if you're still here. Thank
you so much for watching and I will see
you in [music] the next video. Bye-bye.
>> [music]