The man walked ashore and came to a
bustling park. Facing the gazes of the
aunts and the police, he did not feel
embarrassed at all, but was used to it
because he had experienced such things
many times. The man named Henry was an
old monster who lived for 200 years and
possessed an immortal body. The thing he
did not lack the most was time. He
traveled around the world and spoke
countless languages. He searched for the
secret to his immortality. The only
problem was that people around him had
changed, but he was still a handsome
man. Today, Henry took the subway to
work as usual. Henry sat next to a
blonde girl. He only glanced at her and
greeted her in fluent Russian. She was
curious how he knew she was Russian.
Henry explained that there was chocolate
on the corner of her mouth and that
there was a halfeaten known chocolate in
her bag. This made the girl immediately
feel good about him. Henry continued to
say that he noticed that her fingers had
marks far apart, but there were no marks
on her chin, so she must be a cello
player. He also wished her a successful
performance tonight. She was even more
delighted after hearing that. She
enthusiastically invited him to watch
her performance and she said that after
the performance they could have a drink
together. He happily accepted the
invitation but the next second the whole
train became a disaster. Henry was
immediately stabbed in the heart by a
steel bar. The girl also died before he
could express his feelings. She died.
Henry had witnessed countless deaths in
his life, but he was an immortal with
the supernatural power of unlimited
resurrection. This skill began 200 years
ago on a merchant ship of the evil
capitalist Henry as a doctor on board
treated an old man who had a coal but
the captain insisted that the old man
had chalera so he wanted to throw him
into the sea to feed the fish. Henry
defended the cause and was shot dead by
the captain. Henry was then thrown into
the sea. Since that night, Henry has
been merciful to God. Henry has
undergone a mysterious transformation.
Every time he experiences death, Henry
returns to the same body of water. The
only thing that is a bit awkward is that
every time Henry returns, he is in his
original state. This makes him think
that reincarnation is not a good thing.
On the contrary, he feels cursed. Seeing
the police approaching aggressively,
Henry quickly explained that he did not
do it on purpose. When Henry left the
police station, he turned around and saw
his son Abe coming to pick him up. This
was also the only person who knew
Henry's secret. The two quickly returned
to Abee's antique shop. Henry told Abe
what happened today. Countless personal
experiences have made Henry a true death
researcher. Therefore, Henry also became
a super good forensic doctor. Every day,
Henry works with cold corpses. Henry
believes that to understand death, he
must go to places where there are the
most deaths. At the same time, Detective
Joe arrives at the scene of the
accident. Joe finds Henry's pocket watch
in the train. But at this time, she does
not know who the owner of the watch is.
At this time, Joe's boss comes to tell
her that the forensic doctor at the
scene believes that the dispatcher died
of heart disease. Therefore, they judge
that the train collision was an accident
and not caused by humans. She tells Joe
to go to the forensic office to sign the
dispatcher's cause of death. If there
were no surprises, they could close the
case. Joe had just entered the forensic
office when she received the order. At
this moment, Joe saw Henry performing an
autopsy on the dispatcher. This was the
first time the two had met. They
immediately got to work. After Henry cut
open the dispatcher sternum, he could
tell by the naked eye that there was
something wrong with his death. Henry
meant that he did not die of heart
disease. Then Henry took out a handful
of foam from the corpse. The thick foam
showed that the dispatcher had pulmonary
edema. Therefore, Henry speculated that
he was poisoned, but a toxicology report
was needed to confirm it. Joe was a
little skeptical. Lucas told Joe not to
doubt anything. As long as Henry
confirmed the cause of death, it was
almost certain this meant that the
accident had become a murder case
involving 15 people. At this moment,
Henry received a hidden phone call from
a stranger. Not only did this person
know about the subway accident, he also
knew that Henry had survived. When Henry
heard this, his attitude immediately
changed. Henry asked who he was, but the
person immediately hung up. Henry
panicked and returned to the antique
store and began packing his things.
Henry prepared to take Abe to a strange
city. However, Abe had no intention of
leaving. Abe told Henry that hiding was
not the way. The important thing now was
to find out who this person was and what
his purpose was. But for Henry, the
painful experiences of the past were
still clear. Even though it had been 107
years, Henry thought about being forced
to be a human experiment. Every drop of
blood in his body was drained. His
organs were also dissected in the name
of science. Even though he has an
immortal body, the pain is real. This
makes him extremely scared. OB said that
Henry cannot stay with a dead body all
day. Even though Henry has an immortal
body, Abu will pretend to leave and
leave him. So, Henry needs to stay away
from danger and live his life well.
After Henry thought carefully, he chose
to stay. Joe discovered a suspicious
figure through the subway station's
surveillance camera. He was holding the
pocket watch she found. She told the
technician to enlarge the video first.
Then, she carefully looked at it again
and again. Is this Henry, the person Joe
just met today? The next day, Henry went
to work and received a mysterious letter
with no postmark or return address.
Lucas also did not see anyone delivering
the letter. Henry returned to the office
and opened the envelope. When he saw
what was inside, he was stunned. The
photo was an intimate photo of him and a
girl. This girl was his deceased wife.
The time was 1955. They took a photo
together at a party. He didn't know how
the mysterious person got the photo, but
it was clear that the other party's
purpose was not simple. At the same
time, there was also a newspaper
clipping inside. QED has a proof
commonly used in mathematical proofs.
Henry saw the content in the lower half
of the newspaper clipping and
immediately understood something. Then
Henry went to the morg to pull out
coordinator's body and took a tube of
blood from him because the mysterious
person killed the coordinator to prove
whether Henry was dead or not. So Henry
wanted to find out what kind of poison
he used. And by making a big confession,
he could find the culprit behind the
scene. and the most convenient way to
find the poison was to use the blood of
the dead person. Henry decided to take
advantage of his immortal body to test
the poison himself to find the answer.
After Abe injected blood into Henry's
body, within 5 seconds, he began the
familiar process. Henry was then taken
back by Abe. Fortunately, Henry
discovered that the poison was extracted
from aite flowers. This poison works
very quickly. Just by contact with the
skin, it can enter the circulatory
system causing stomach burns and lung
swelling. However, before Henry could
take the next step, Joe led people to
take Henry to the police station.
Through the pocket watch found and the
things searched in the basement, the
police speculated that Henry was
culprit. At this time, Henry told Joe
that he discovered Akenite based on the
fast acting properties of this poison.
Henry assumed that culprit must have
been on the subway at that time. Henry
was talking very enthusiastically when
he suddenly realized something was
wrong. Why did it seem like he had put
his head in it himself? and the police
thought so too, so they invited him back
to investigate. During the autopsy, why
didn't he hide the truth and say that
the coordinator was poisoned? He
wouldn't do something so stupid as to
hand himself over to the police. Joe
thought Henry's analysis was reasonable.
At the moment, the police didn't have
any solid evidence to prove it, so they
could only let Henry leave first. Henry
returned to the workshop and carefully
examined the coordinator's body with his
colleagues. Sure enough, they found a
needle mark on his ear, and there was
also a clear fingerprint next to it.
Obviously, this was left by the
murderer. The next day, Henry brought
the evidence to the police station and
hoped that Joe could quickly find the
culprit based on fingerprints. They
quickly found a man named Han, but his
house was closed and there was no one
there. Henry discovered a dead rat from
poisoning in his backyard. Next to it
was a room full of akenite plants. Going
inside, they also saw a room full of
laboratory equipment. Obviously, this
was where poison was made. At this
moment, the sound of the door opening
came from outside. Immediately after,
they saw Han entering. Joe raised his
gun to arrest Han, but he threw the
bottle of poison at him. At this time,
Henry was completely unable to chase the
culprit because the poison had already
begun to enter Joe's circulatory system.
Henry only had 1 minute left. Henry took
the ethanol on the table and poured it
on Joe's hand. Using the fastest speed
to neutralize the toxicity of the poison
at this time, he was able to save Joe's
life. Through investigation, Han was a
chemical expert. Han's wife fell onto
the subway lines 3 years ago and died.
The train driver who hit her and killed
her was the dispatcher who had just
died. So, the collision was planned by
Han. But Henry was a little confused.
Henry thought the mysterious person was
targeting him. The police quickly
discovered more poison. Judging by the
volume, it was probably two gallons.
There were also traces of ethanol
inside. Henry speculated that Han wanted
to turn the poison of the akenite flour
into a solvent to create a large amount
of poison. Perhaps Han's goal was to
kill more people. At this time, Henry
saw many strange drawings on the table.
He slipped one over and found that its
shape was exactly the same as the one on
the ceiling of the central station he
had visited many years ago. This was the
place where Han's wife was killed.
Everyone immediately realized the
seriousness of the problem. The police
quickly surrounded the central station.
The lobby was packed with people and Han
was nowhere to be seen. Henry observed
that there were ventilation holes all
over the walls. Tonight seemed special.
It was cold, but the air conditioner was
on. Gallon guessed that Han had turned
the poison into a solvent so that it
could spread in the air. Then the two
went to the top floor where the
ventilation system was installed, but
they didn't find anything unusual. Henry
thought he was thinking too much.
Suddenly, after Joe fell down, Henry was
treated as free labor. He forced Henry
to put poison in the ventilation system.
Henry originally intended to use reason
to convince Han, but he didn't listen.
Han threatened Henry that he had a gun
in his hand. Then Han quickly and
accurately shot Henry in the chest. At
the crucial moment, Henry stood up with
strong will and jumped down, hugging
Han. The two immediately lost their
breath and Henry entered the time
tunnel. When Joe woke up in the
hospital, the first thing she saw was a
handsome man standing by the window.
Henry told Joe that she had been shot
and Han realized his mistake at the last
minute and jumped off the building. The
poison had not been released, but Joe
always felt that something was wrong.
She vaguely saw the two people hugging
and jumping off the building. Henry
thought it might be a side effect of the
anesthesia. At this moment, the hidden
person's phone called again and told
Henry that they were the same. Both of
them wanted death to be something they
could not choose. They shared the same
pain, curse, and torment. Since they
could not find a way to resolve it now,
they should find some joy together and
be soulmates forever. Henry did not know
what his true purpose was. Henry then
said goodbye to Joe and prepared to
leave. Henry walked out of the hospital
room and was immediately lost in his
memories. He had experienced countless
deaths, countless sufferings, and
torments in his life. but his only
confidant was his wife. The two met
during World War II. Henry, a war
doctor, saw his wife save a newborn
baby. They fell in love and became a
couple at first sight. The baby they
saved was Abe. That is, Abe was now old
and Henry was still the same as when he
was young. After Joe was discharged from
the hospital, she went to Henry and
returned her pocket watch to him. Joe
also invited Henry to do her forensics.
With Abe's help, Henry readily agreed. A
fat, agile man was hacked to death with
an axe. But Henry only opened the
victim's mouth to look, and he confirmed
that he died of an accident. The
policeman asked Henry with a bewildered
expression if he had looked carefully.
There was an axe stuck in the victim's
head. This was definitely a murder. Joe
also said that there were witnesses who
heard the victim arguing with his
neighbor 20 minutes before he died.
Henry thought about it and explained it
one by one. Looking at the victim's
clothes, Henry knew that he was a
football fan. Henry guessed that there
must have been a fierce game last night.
Hansen later confirmed that the game was
indeed fierce. The victim's blood
alcohol test was over the standard,
indicating that he was probably drunk at
the time. He mistook the power outage
for a problem with his satellite
antenna. The tar on his knees showed
that he had climbed onto the roof. Wood
splinters between his white teeth showed
that he had an axe in his mouth. Damp
surface and wet leaves showed that he
slipped and fell from the ladder. The
slight fracture of the 15th vertebrae
showed that he fell backwards. At this
moment, the axe fell due to gravity.
Coincidentally, it hit the victim
between the eyebrows. So, Henry
confirmed that the victim died of an
accident. Hansen said the coroner had
given the results of the examination, so
they had nothing more to say. So, they
should go home, take a shower, and go to
bed early. Just as the two were about to
leave, Henry called them back and said
that Victoria's cause of death was very
suspicious. Last night, Victoria cried
out in pain, begging the person on the
other end of the phone to pick up. Then
she urged the driver to drive faster.
But the taxi just arrived at Victoria
Bridge and asked to stop immediately.
Before the driver could stop the car
completely, she hurriedly opened the car
door and ran out. Then in the driver's
horrified eyes, she climbed onto the
railing. Then passers by heard a scream
followed by the sound of falling into
the water. The next day, Victoria's body
was found on the shore. Joe said that
there was a witness who confirmed that
Victoria jumped in. But from Henry's
professional perspective, he discovered
that there were paint chips between her
fingernails. This type of paint was not
allowed to be used after 1970. This
showed that Victoria's fingernails had
scratched off at least 12 layers of
paint and the wear marks on her shoes
showed that she was struggling. Henry
also discovered that Victoria's fracture
extended from her big toe to her tibia.
This showed that when her body was
impacted, she faced the bridge. He had
lived for 200 years and had never seen
anyone jump for a long time and then
turn around halfway. So Henry speculated
that Victoria had been murdered. After
Joe heard this, she decided to start an
investigation. But Hansen thought that
Victoria might have turned around and
slipped and fell. Based on Henry's words
alone, they could not conclude that it
was murder. But Joe said Henry was never
wrong and she turned around and walked
out. When Joe returned to the police
station, her superiors looked for Joe to
talk. She said that at that time many
people saw Victoria jumping off the
bridge by herself, so they didn't need
to waste their energy on such a case.
She also told Joe to be stronger in her
work. Joe couldn't let a forensic
judgment affect her. They still had many
really important cases to investigate.
At the same time, in the forensic room,
Lucas told Henry that the police had
called and hoped they would give the
result that the victim had done
something stupid. At that moment, Henry
saw Victoria's parents coming to pick up
her body. He quickly ran out to cover
the body to avoid the heartbreaking
scene. Victoria's parents said that
their daughter couldn't do anything
stupid because she had just gotten a
master's degree in classical literature.
She was going to study abroad in Paris
soon. They asked if there were any other
unexpected things that had happened.
Henry didn't know how to answer, so he
just advised them to discuss this matter
with police. Seeing the parents of the
victims in pain, Henry expressed his
sympathy for their pain. To reassure
them, Henry specially went to the bridge
that night to find out the truth about
Victoria's jump. He carefully climbed up
the bridge railing and indeed discovered
fingernail scratches. There were also
men's shoe prints beside them. Just as
Henry was feeling pleased, he looked up
and saw a climbing lock. Henry spent a
lot of effort to finally get the
evidence, but he almost fell down
because he slipped. But then Henry
climbed up. The next second, Henry was
hit by a car and the driver was
bewildered and scared. He quickly got
out of the car to check. At this time,
Henry was sitting on the time machine
and returning to the familiar area. The
driver walked around the car, even
examined the undercarriage, but he
couldn't find a single hair. He clearly
felt like he had hit someone, but there
was nothing. Could it be that he had hit
a ghost at this time, Henry hurriedly
got into the car and was picked up by
Abe. The next day, as soon as Henry went
to work, he was informed that the nail
polish in Victoria's fingernails matched
the nail polish used on the bridge. And
they also discovered something
surprising. Lucas took out a piece of
skin that didn't belong to Victoria
under the cuticle. They guessed that she
had left it when she struggled with the
murderer before she died. The new
discovery made Henry very happy, but
soon after, Henry was in no mood anymore
when there was a gift on his desk. Henry
was immediately worried and scared. When
he saw what was inside, he remembered
the mysterious person's phone call. Who
was this person? Why did it feel like he
was always following Henry? Henry
hurried home to share this with Abe. The
feeling of being held in someone's palm
was worse than not being able to die.
Abe discovered that the letter was
written on stripe paper. The watermark
on it was also from an earlier period.
Just when they were about to find out
the origin of the paper, Joe found it.
Even though he had been warned by his
superiors not to investigate the girl's
case, Joe still believed Henry's
judgment. For some reason, Joe found out
that the day Victoria had an accident
was the day she was preparing to leave
for Paris, and the boarding procedures
had already been completed. For someone
about to do something foolish, doing
such things was obviously strange. So,
the two went to Victoria's school to
investigate. When they arrived at the
dormatory, they found her parents
packing up her belongings. Henry
carefully discovered that Victoria loved
mountain climbing, but her parents had
just said that she and her boyfriend had
broken up a long time ago. So, who took
her photo? There was another suspicious
detail here. Joe asked them if Victoria
had any other hobbies. The father said
they hadn't been in contact for a long
time. Victoria was busy writing her
thesis all day and translating an
ancient manuscript found in Egypt with
the professor. At this time, Victoria's
mother showed Henry a photo of her when
she was young. Henry saw Victoria's
mother in pain, so he leaned closer and
said that they would quickly find out
who did this. After they went out, Joe
was a little worried and told Henry not
to promise Victoria's mother like that.
Joe secretly investigated. If her
superiors found out, she would be in big
trouble. Moreover, there were many cases
like this that went unsolved for years.
But for Henry, the thing he didn't lack
the most was time. So Henry and Joe went
to Victoria's school to investigate.
They learned from Victoria's parents
that she had been with her professor
recently. The two of them, along with a
blonde young man on the stairs, went to
Professor James to verify. At the same
time, the young man praised Professor
James to the fullest. He was full of
admiration for Professor James. He
expressed his utmost respect to
Professor James. Jack entered the
password and opened the door of the
research room. When Professor James saw
Joe, he quickly ended the lecture. When
he learned that they came to ask about
Victoria's problem, Professor James said
that she was one of his most intelligent
students. They had recently studied
ancient manuscripts together. Victoria
was deeply attracted to the content
inside. They even wrote a related essay.
It was about to be published, but
unfortunately, Victoria was dead now.
The signatures on it were those of
Professor James and Victoria. After
Professor James finished speaking, he
naturally put the pen in his mouth. His
hand removed the entangled scarf. Henry
asked James with some doubt if he
smoked. James said he didn't smoke. When
Henry asked about the relationship
between James and Victoria, he clearly
hesitated a bit before saying that it
was just a private colleague
relationship. They didn't interact
often. And when Victoria had the
incident, James and his wife were at the
opera house. However, after they went
out, Henry kept saying that Professor
James and Victoria had a secret
relationship. There were cigarette
stains on Victoria's bed sheet. Joe said
that it was also possible that Victoria
smoked herself. Henry had checked
Victoria's teeth and lungs and
determined that she didn't smoke, but
Professor James sometimes couldn't help
himself, and the photo of climbing in
Victoria's room was taken by James. The
scarf Victoria was wearing was also the
one on James' desk. Joe admired Henry's
observation skills. What made Joe admire
him even more was that Henry had
secretly obtained a DNA test sample. The
results showed that the sample on
Victoria's fingernails completely
matched the sample on James' pen. It
seemed that the case was about to be
solved. To determine whether James'
alibi was true or not, the two went to
his house to visit his wife. The wife
testified for him without hesitation,
but Henry said that her husband had
cheated on her, so she didn't need to
lie for him. The woman didn't understand
what Henry meant. Henry explained that
there were two programs on the table.
One was crumpled and the other was brand
new. This proved that she had waited for
James at the door, but he didn't show
up. Henry also guessed that she knew
that her husband was having an affair
and that she had tried to save their
relationship because the photos on the
table were all covered with dust. Only
one photo of them together when they
were young was dust-free. Henry guessed
that this was a new photo that she had
put up to remind her of the days when
they were in love. Seeing this, she no
longer hid it. She admitted that she was
not with her husband that night. James
was quickly summoned to the police
station to be investigated from murder.
Not only did James not admit that he was
the murderer, he also said that Victoria
was the woman he loved most. But James
was already a 65year-old man while
Victoria was only 22. James did not want
to waste Victoria's youth, so he chose
to break up. After listening, Henry said
that everything James said was true.
Henry believed that Victoria was not
killed by James. At this moment, James'
lawyer came to bail him out.
Unexpectedly, this would lead to a
greater tragedy. At the same time, Abbe
found out that the paper was a product
of a paper mill in Milan, but the paper
mill was destroyed during World War II.
The text at the top of the paper was the
logo of a local hotel called Monontto.
Unfortunately, it had closed 60 years
ago, Henry immediately remembered that
in 1945, after he and his wife had made
love in the hotel, he left a letter for
her and left alone. Unexpectedly, after
waking up, his wife had changed. She
didn't care about his special identity,
and she didn't care about the outcome.
She believed that the meaning of life
was the journey, not how long it could
last. Just cherish the time you can
spend together. Henry had been
enlightened since then. He believed in
James love for Victoria. James suggested
breaking up, but Victoria didn't want
to. Someone took advantage of this to
lure Victoria to the bridge. Victoria
was surprised when she saw that it
wasn't the person she wanted to see.
Victoria would definitely use something
to resist. Then Henry used force to open
Victoria's mouth, and sure enough, he
pulled out a piece of human flesh. Henry
asked Lucas to compare his jeans with
James'. At this moment, Joe came and
told them that they didn't need it
anymore because they had discovered
James' body. The police thought that he
committed suicide because the students
said they saw him mentally depressed and
there was a suicide note on the table.
But after Henry checked, he said that
James was murdered. Everyone was a
little suspicious. Henry said that
someone had injected James with
sedatives and the cut on his wrist was
from the inside out. Henry had seen too
many people commit suicide with a razor,
and they were all cuts from the outside
in, and the murderer was left-handed.
Joe didn't understand how Henry knew.
Henry said that the tea in the suicide
note was all tilted backwards. Moreover,
there was a word used incorrectly. James
would never make such a mistake. After
that, Joe considered this place a crime
scene and asked everyone to review wall
to review all the surveillance thing and
leaving the building within 2 hours.
They quickly discovered that James's
wife had been here. At the same time,
Henry discovered that James' thesis had
been torn. This made Henry suddenly
think of something. At this time,
someone sneaked into James' research
room. This person was Jack. Just as Jack
was about to log into the computer,
Henry interrupted. To hide his anxiety,
he deliberately said that he came to
help James publish his thesis, but Henry
made it clear that Jack was left-handed,
but he used his right hand to type on
the keyboard. When James fell in love
with Victoria and decided to co-author
the thesis with her, Jack was sad
because his name was not on it. So, Jack
called Victoria and told her that he
wanted to jump off the bridge. He knew
she was kind, so she would come to stop
him. He took the opportunity to kill
her. Jack did not admit that these
things had anything to do with him.
Henry pressed closer and told Jack that
he knew that after James was taken away
by the police for investigation, they
would find out about him sooner or
later. So, he had created a scene where
James did something foolish. Before
that, Jack had been praising James
non-stop to escape suspicion. Jack's
motive for doing so was to have his name
on the thesis and turn it into his own
property. Jack saw that the matter had
been exposed, so he stopped pretending.
Jack secretly took out a box cutter and
controlled Henry when he wasn't paying
attention. Although Henry had an
immortal body, when he looked up and saw
the surveillance camera above, he was
extremely scared. If he died now, his
secret would be discovered. Henry
struggled with Jack. Although Anna saw
Henry being cornered from the
surveillance camera, their whole team
had acted and caught Jack at crucial
moment. Luckily, Henry only suffered
superficial injuries, otherwise he
wouldn't have been able to speak
clearly, even if he kept his mouth shut.
Henry looked up at the surveillance
camera again. For the first time, Henry
felt that death was terrible. The truth
about Victoria's death was finally
revealed. Henry personally handed over
Victoria's relics to her parents. The
pain of losing a loved one could not be
erased, only hoping that over time the
wound would gradually heal. When he
returned home, Henry also thought about
his wife. Unfortunately, no one else
could die and come back to life.
Fortunately, AB was by Henry's side, so
he was not too lonely. At this moment,
Henry received a phone call from the
mysterious person. The other party still
knew everything about Henry. Henry did
not know what person wanted to do, but
Henry knew that the person had lived for
2,000 years. Henry wanted them to meet,
but he was rejected. Then the mysterious
person hung up. Henry did not expect
that at this moment the mysterious
person was less than 10 meters away from
him. David had just gotten out of the
taxi when suddenly the briefcase in his
hand was stolen. David did not choose to
call the police, but chased after the
thief. In just a few seconds, David had
pinned the thief to the ground. The
young thief was beaten so much that he
had to beg David to stop. David's body
suddenly seemed to lose control. David's
whole body trembled and he spurted blood
from his nose and then fell unconscious.
Considering David's death to be unusual,
his body was taken to the forensic room.
At the same time, Joe also captured the
thief because there were no bruises or
any injuries on David's body except for
his slightly worn knuckles from beating
someone. David's bone density was almost
that of a young man. The only
abnormality was David's brain. Henry
discovered amaloid plaques in David's
brain tissue. At that time, David seemed
to be suffering from Alzheimer's,
Parkinson's, and Huntington's disease.
At the same time, Henry also found some
unknown mixture in David's stomach.
There was a smell of artificial vanilla
inside. Just then, Lucas came to inform
them that David's son had come to claim
the body. Mark said that for many years,
David had been taking the train from the
countryside to his mother every night.
But 2 years ago, after Mark's mother
passed away, David seemed to have become
a different person, and he had forgotten
about them. To ease this sad scene, Joe
asked to see David's briefcase. After
Mark's permission, they opened it.
Inside was a photo of a woman. It was
Mark's mother. In addition, Joe
discovered a mysterious business card
with no address or contact information.
There was only a picture of a snake
holding its tail, symbolizing eternal
continuity. They were not sure if this
was related to David's unusual body. To
solve this doubt, Joe and Henry went to
the scene where David had an accident.
They found that the situation here was a
bit unsuitable for old people who hated
the city. Just as they were puzzled,
they suddenly saw a lady getting out of
a luxury car. When she left secretly,
the two of them quietly followed. Then
they discovered a symbol of a snake with
a tail on an anti- theft door. It seemed
that this was the mysterious place on
the business card. However, when they
opened the door, there was a bit of a
surprise. This was a lavishly decorated
clinic. A promotional video was playing
on a screen. Do you want to live
forever? After Henry heard this, he
became even more suspicious of what they
were up to. Next, the two of them went
to visit Dr. Gartner. When Henry asked
Gartner about the main ingredient of the
medicine, he refused to answer on the
grounds that it was inconvenient to
disclose patent, but he could be sure
that the rejuvenation medicine was
completely harmless. Otherwise, he would
not have taken it himself every day. Joe
planned to bring a sample back for
testing. Gartner said that the demand
for this medicine was too great.
Customers had lined up from America to
Central Africa, so they were really
helpless unless they had a search
warrant. The two helpless people were
about to leave when Henry suddenly saw
the lady just now enter. Henry
immediately came up with a plan and went
over. He used his handsome appearance to
talk to the lady. After gaining her
trust, he deliberately created an
incident. Just like that, Henry was able
to get a bag of rejuvenation medicine.
At the same time, Joe also got Gartner's
fingerprints. At the same time, Lucas
was checking the number of corpses when
he discovered that two corpses had
disappeared. He panicked and hurriedly
asked his colleagues if anyone had seen
them. But the signature book last night
was Lucas's. This time, Lucas was in big
trouble. After one night, Henry
extracted and separated the compounds in
the rejuvenation potion. He discovered
that they were all extracted from cheap
medicinal herbs. This showed that Gier
had lied. Gartner had cheated in the
production of the potion. There might be
other ingredients that caused real
damage to David's brain. However,
through the fingerprints on the name,
Joe found out that Gear was just a
fraud. Gartner had never received any
medical training. It seemed that they
had to investigate Gartner thoroughly.
So, the two went to Gangar's private
villa. At this time, Gartner was having
a pool party with a group of boys and
girls, but Joe exposed his dark history
with Gartner in front of his girlfriend.
Gyner was immediately a little worried.
Gartner told his girlfriend to go down
to the pool to wait for him. Then,
Gartner told the two that David's death
had nothing to do with him. Gyner was
scared and said that he would tell
everything he knew, but they needed to
change places. Gartner went to change
his clothes first. While the two were
waiting downstairs, they saw the lady
again, but she had no impression of
Henry and was walking around like she
was drunk. Strangely, Henry discovered
that the glass of water she was holding
was just soda water. While Gartner was
suspicious, he heard a scream coming
from upstairs. Realizing that something
was wrong, the two quickly ran upstairs.
But when they opened the door, they
witnessed a horrifying scene. Gartner
was lying in a pool of blood and had
stopped breathing. Henry discovered that
someone had attacked Gartner from
behind. This person used his arm to
strangle Gartner and then attacked him.
Henry then used tweezers to remove half
a disposable scalpel blade from
Gartner's wound. This proved that the
killer had medical knowledge. Henry
returned to the office and examined
Gartner's brain. Henry discovered that
Gartner and David had the same
neurodeenerative disease as if someone
was eating their brains. The only
connection between Gartner and David was
that they had both taken the elixir of
youth. What exactly caused their brains
to be so shattered? This reminded Henry
of a colleague of his aundred years ago.
This person had tuberculosis and was in
constant pain. In order to feel better,
he went to a private clinic every day
for electrocomvulsive therapy. Henry
told him that this method was
unscientific. Henry wanted to send him
away. They could definitely find a
better treatment, but Henry's colleagues
said that tuberculosis was incurable.
They didn't even know what caused the
disease. They were indeed people who
valued science until it disappointed
them. Henry immediately woke up and
rushed to tell Joe the truth that
tuberculosis was not known to be caused
by bacteria and could be cured until
1882. It took the world another 20 years
to learn that it could be transmitted
through the mill of infected cows.
Referring to the case they were
investigating, Henry explained that
perhaps their investigation had been
wrong from the start. They had always
been looking for the compound in the
elixir that caused brain damage. But if
the elixir itself had been contaminated
with brain, it was neither a bacteria
nor a fungus. It was simply made up of a
small amount of protein. So no test
could detect it. But when people were
infected with brain, they would develop
strange neurological symptoms because it
was eroding and perforating the human
brain. This was the reason why David and
Garner's brains were shattered. To
contract Breen, one had to eat infected
tissue. And Breen's existence in human
nerve tissue means that those people are
eating the spinal cord. Henry thinks
that the important thing now is to find
out where the spinal cord comes from.
So, the two of them hurried to the morg.
Lucas was having a headache about the
missing bodies when he suddenly heard
Henry ask how many bodies had been lost
recently. Lucas just told the truth and
found out that in the past year, 12
bodies had been lost. All of them were
anonymous and unclaimed. Henry asked
Lucas to recall all the details of the
day the bodies were lost. Just when
Lucas mentioned eating donuts, Henry
realized something was wrong. Why would
Lucas, who didn't like sweets, buy
donuts a few kilometers away? Lucas
suddenly remembered that the driver
named Anton who gave them the bodies was
the one who gave him the donuts. Joe
quickly issued a nationwide wanted order
for Anton. Very quickly, the police
surrounded Anton. At the same time, they
also discovered that in the ambulance,
Anton was driving, there was a body that
had just had its brain removed. Faced
with solid evidence, Anton admitted to
the crime of stealing the body and
murder. Anton said that he also made the
rejuvenation drug. He said that he had
advanced training in chemistry and was a
chemist. But after Anton moved to the
US, he could only work as a driver. So
Anton came up with this way to make
quick money to determine whether Anton's
testimony was true or false. Henry asked
Joe to ask Anton some professional
knowledge about bone marrow extraction,
but Anton's answers were completely
inconsistent. though he was not the real
mastermind. At this moment, the police
brought over a list of all the customers
who bought the rejuvenation drug. Henry
glanced at it and suddenly ran away. It
turned out that Henry had seen Abee's
name on it. Henry ran straight to the
antique store and asked why Abe used
those rejuvenation drugs. Wouldn't it be
nice to die naturally and gracefully?
Abe said he didn't do it for himself.
Abeay was just worried that no one would
take care of Henry after he died. Henry
was deeply moved by these words.
Fortunately, Abe, as the son of a
forensic scientist, wasn't that stupid.
Abe didn't believe that the rejuvenation
drug had such a miraculous effect. So,
he specifically sought out their chemist
to explain it to him. Henry asked which
chemist. Abe said that it was a pretty
girl. Henry immediately realized
something was wrong. Through comparing
portraits, they quickly discovered that
the chemist was Garner's beautiful
assistant. Sasha was a Ukrainian
chemist. Sasha moved to the United
States 2 years ago on a medical student
visa and has been living with her
brother. Sasha's brother, Anton, was
just arrested. At the same time, Sasha
went to the police station to visit her
brother. Anton told her that he had
confessed to all his crimes. He told her
to quickly sell the remaining drugs and
leave with the money. Sasha was very
obedient to her brother. Although she
was reluctant, she still left with a
heavy heart. Unexpectedly, Sasha was
caught by Obached
subway station. Abe quietly retreated
and called Henry. When they found out
about Sasha's whereabouts, they quickly
ran over. Sasha said that Anton did all
this for her. They were just too scared
that these people did not deserve to
die. Seeing the subway slowly
approaching, Sasha was about to jump
onto the tracks. At this moment, Henry
rushed over and hugged Sasha. The case
was finally over. The remaining people
were rescued in time, so no accidents
happened. The newlyweds just wanted to
buy a house to live in, but the broker
took them to an old neighborhood. The
broker also said that this place was
being eyed by a big boss who was about
to be redeveloped, so buying it now
would be a good deal. However, as soon
as they entered the house, they smelled
a pungent, unpleasant odor. Then they
witnessed a horrifying scene. They saw a
rotting corpse on the floor. The
victim's body was full of wounds and
needles. Joe quickly went to the scene
with Henry. This was a gathering place
for drug addicts and homeless people, so
almost every week there were murders.
The victim's face was gnawed by rats to
the point of being unrecognizable. The
police were unable to identify him for
the time being. They then took the body
to the forensic department. At this
time, Henry discovered something
strange. The poison he injected did not
enter his bloodstream, but was
concentrated near his muscle tissue.
This meant that he might have been
injected after death. Just then, Lucas
arrived and said that he had found the
victim's identity. The victim's name was
Ron, a fitness trainer. He was obviously
murdered. Now, they needed to wait for
Ron's toxicology report to find out who
was responsible. Then, Ron's girlfriend
came to claim his body. They were
planning to get married next spring, but
this happened unexpectedly. She could
confirm that Ron did not use drugs.
Although he had a criminal record, he
started working hard after he got out of
prison. Joe asked Ron's girlfriend if he
had acted unusually the last time they
saw each other. She remembered that when
he left the apartment, he was arguing
with someone on the phone. She didn't
know who. Ron had been missing since
that night. Next, Henry and Joe went to
the gym where Ron worked. Joan said he
hadn't seen Ron for 4 days. Someone like
Ron, who had never missed volunteer
activities, suddenly missing. Must be
something bad. The last time they saw
each other was at 9:00 p.m. 4 days ago
because Joan had the key here. Joan was
preparing to close the shop at that
time, so he remembered it very clearly.
When they asked Joan if Ron had a
conflict with anyone, Joan said it might
be Tommy. Tommy was a famous local real
estate developer. Tommy bought half of
the old neighborhood, including the gym.
Henry asked what happened to the wound,
the corner of Tommy's eye. Joan said he
got hurt while teaching the kids boxing.
Then Henry and Joe went to a nearby
grocery store. In such a complicated
place, the grocery store was a
combination of a bank, post office, and
a supermarket. Seeing the rubber road
being paved by workers, Henry
immediately remembered Ron's shoes.
Therefore, it is speculated that the
location of the body was very close to
this playground, and the distance was
enough for the murderer to make Ron
enter the apartment. At the same time,
Joe also found that Ron's phone was
still ringing somewhere nearby. In other
words, this place was most likely the
first crime scene. Then, Joe called
Ron's phone number. Very quickly, there
was a slight vibration on the ground.
After a while of searching, Henry
finally found the phone. The call
history showed that Ron's last call was
to Tommy. So, as a suspect, Tommy was
invited to the police station for
questioning. Tommy said he didn't know
Ron. Tommy couldn't possibly have killed
Ron. Tommy received many angry phone
calls every day. He didn't even know
where those people got his phone number.
Now, Tommy's construction site had
become a crime scene, causing him heavy
losses. Tommy hoped that the police
could solve this case as soon as
possible. Tommy then prepared to leave
with his lawyer. They could not detain
him just based on a phone call Ron made
to Tommy. The police had no direct
evidence, so they could only release
Tommy. Joe quickly found another
suspect, Jon. Jon had previously been
involved in the Pagarelli family
business. Next, the two of them
monitored Jon 24 hours. That night, they
found him receiving a large package from
Tommy and leaving. They followed Jon to
the gym. They saw him take the package
in and leave empty-handed 2 minutes
later. When he drove away, two of them
forced their way into the gym. Sure
enough, they found the package in J's
locker. Seeing that there was 6 million
in cash inside, Joe guessed that he had
bought the murderer. Then, Joe took Jon
to the Henry Morde and pulled out Ron's
body. After Jon saw it, he immediately
felt a little nauseous, but his reaction
was more fear. Henry asked Jon if it was
worth killing his friend for 50,000. Jon
said he didn't understand what Henry was
saying, but the skin tissue found under
Ron's ring matched Jon's, but Jon
insisted that he didn't kill Ron. Henry
realized that Jon didn't seem to be
lying. The only person who knew that Ron
intended to ruin the deal was Tommy. So,
the next day, under police surveillance,
Jon met Tommy alone. Jon asked Tommy why
he killed Ron. Tommy only thought that
Jon was not satisfied with payment, but
he didn't admit anything else. At this
moment, Henry saw a familiar boy playing
tennis. So, he went up and asked the boy
if he knew Ron. The boy smiled and was
about to answer when he suddenly turned
around as if he saw something scary. The
boy didn't say a word and ran away.
Henry saw Jon leaning against the
opposite car. When Henry turned around
in doubt, he saw more important
information. The shadow on the wall was
exactly the same as in the room where
Ron was murdered. Therefore, Henry was
certain that the boy definitely knew who
the murderer was. Thinking about seeing
the boy run away in fear, Henry suddenly
realized that the boy might be in
danger. They followed the direction the
boy ran away to search, but only saw the
bicycle thrown on the side of the road.
Only then did the two realize that
something was wrong. Henry thought about
the boy being scared by John standing in
front of the grocery store just now,
unless the boy looked different at that
time. At this time, the grocery store
had hung a sign that said he was out of
business. This further increased the
boss's suspicions. Joe used the excuse
of smelling smoke and rushed into the
grocery store. As soon as she entered,
Henry discovered the boy's tennis ball.
At this time, the boss was threatening
the boy in the basement. Just as he was
about to kill him to silence him, Henry
rushed in. The boy was finally out of
danger. The boss ran out of the tunnel
and onto the street. Henry chased
closely behind. Unexpectedly, the boss
who was about to die said Tommy's name.
The hard one clue was cut off. Joe
thought that he deserved it for
accepting bribes and harming innocent
people. Henry felt that he was just a
pawn manipulated by others. The evildoer
was still at large, but he had to pay
with his life. Fortunately, owned from
the local trade council confessed to
Tommy's bribery. Plus, what happened to
Ron? The nearby residents no longer
wanted to sell their land. The gym was
conveniently kept and the poor children
had a place to rest and relax. This also
reflects the gap between rich and poor
in real society. The ones who are hurt
are always the poor. Gloria is the wife
of a prestigious family that has
selflessly donated countless famous
paintings to the museum for many years.
The mayor specially organized a charity
party to thank her. All the celebrities
and nobles attended, but Gloria always
had a sardonic tongue. Even her deceased
husband was mercilessly cursed by her.
Her sharp words left the market
speechless. This made many guests feel
dissatisfied. As soon as the party
reached its climax, Gloria was found
dead in the cold hallway. Although the
police immediately sealed off lace, many
high-ranking officials who came to see
her ruined the scene. Afterwards, Lucas
took Gloria's body to the morg. Her
pelvis and spine had obvious fractures.
There were two to three dozen large and
small bruises on her body, including
those on her hands and forearms. So,
they judged that Gloria had been
murdered. Gloria was the only surviving
ays of the Carnegie family, the founder
of the New York steel industry. Everyone
knew about their family's wealth and
power. At this moment, a beautiful girl
was sitting in the tea room of the
forensic department. When Lucas came to
pour coffee and saw her, he was
immediately fascinated. Lucas took the
initiative to introduce himself as the
chief forensic doctor at Gloria's crime
scene. Lucas was not on guard and told
her everything. Just when he wanted to
go further with the girl, she packed her
bag and prepared to leave. Before going
out, she made a mysterious phone call.
Early the next morning, the news of
Gloria's murder was on the front page.
Gloria's son, Conrad, angrily appeared
at police chief's office and criticized
them for leaking this matter, which
greatly affected their family. Henry
also suspected that someone was talking
too much and leaking the news. At this
time, Lucas came to say that he was
wrong and had even prepared a
resignation letter, but Henry
interrupted Lucas's next stupid thought.
Henry told Lucas to go back to the
office first and not to tell anyone
about this. Then Henry took the blame
for Lucas, but Conrad did not accept
Henry's apology. Because of this, Conrad
took away Henry's access to Gloria's
body. Joe told Henry not to be sad.
Although he did not have access to the
body, it did not mean that they could
not investigate together. The only
problem was that they had to go to the
museum. After Henry heard this, he
stopped. But in order to let Gloria rest
in peace, Henry still decided to go
there. When Henry arrived at the museum
door, he could not help but recall the
past. At that time, he and his wife had
traveled a long way to the museum, but
because they did not have a new
invitation, they were refused entry. I
don't know what Henry said, but he told
them to go. This was also the first time
Henry met Gloria. The inside was still
as splendid as before. It was just that
people from back then were missing. Joe
reminded him and pulled Henry back to
reality. He only glanced at the photo
and found a clue. Following the
direction of these traces, he guessed
that Gloria had crawled here. The
starting point was this spiral
staircase. Henry guessed that Gloria had
been pushed down the stairs at that
time. She was seriously injured and
definitely couldn't move, but someone
forced her to crawl forward. After she
crawled 3 m into the gallery, she died
from exhaustion. So Henry guessed that
there was another person here at that
time. At this moment, Joe received a
call from a colleague. They discovered
from the surveillance camera that after
Gloria left the room, a man followed her
to the east side of the gallery. He
sneaked behind the guard and walked
without being detected. This man was
Gloria's niece's boyfriend, Lance. The
police quickly brought Lance in for
questioning. Lance was a poor kid from
the slums. Hansen found a $30,000
diamond ring at Lance's house. So, they
guessed that Lance was discovered
stealing and killed Gloria. But Lance
said that this was an engagement gift
that Gloria gave him. Gloria's
girlfriend's father did not agree to let
him be with her. The two of them knew
that Gloria believed in free love. So
that day, Lance bravely went to ask her
permission. At that time, Gloria gave
Lance the ring and said that he had to
follow his heart. Lance only felt that
Gloria was very strange at that time.
Someone who was usually sharp tonged
like her spoke hesitantly. She also said
that there was a burning smell in the
gallery. Henry heard this outside and
suddenly realized that his previous
guess was wrong. Gloria might not have
been pushed downstairs. Gloria said that
she smelled something burning because
she had olfactory hallucinations. This
is a typical symptom of a stroke. To
confirm this guess, Henry needed to do a
test on Gloria's liver. However, Henry
currently had no access to Gloria's
body, so Henry sought out Lucas for
help. Joe also sought out Gloria's
niece, hoping to learn about her
medication status. However, Gloria's
niece did not know anything about her
condition. She only knew that Gloria was
an unfeing woman. Joe quickly found out
that Gloria had removed her son, Conrad,
from her will. Conrad was trying to
regain control of his mother's villa. He
was currently selling the property. At
this time, Henry thought of Abe, saying
that he would go to the auction. So
Henry quickly called Abe. Henry hoped
that Abe could take a picture of the
medicines stored in Gloria's medicine
cabinet. After Henry looked at it, he
did not find any medicine that caused
the stroke. Just when Henry thought he
had made a mistake, he suddenly saw
Conrad's trembling hands in the office.
Then when Conrad was about to leave,
Henry stepped forward to stop him. Henry
asked if the epilepsy medicine was fenny
to. Conrad was right. But millions of
people took it. Why did Henry asked
Conrad this? Henry said, "Because it was
this medicine that killed Conrad's
mother." At this time, everyone was
surprised. Later, Conrad was detained
for questioning. He admitted that his
relationship with his mother was not
good, but he was also the one who
understood his mother the most. When his
mother threatened to remove him from the
will, he had been removed long ago. He
was one of the people who hoped that she
would live the longest. Conrad had the
best chance because only when his mother
was alive would he have the chance to
change his will. The police had no solid
evidence, so they could only let Conrad
leave temporarily. Then Joe and Henry
went to the morg downstairs. They met
Lucas rushing back from outside. Lucas,
who was always strict with himself,
would never be late. Under Henry's
questioning, Lucas said that he had just
gone to the funeral home to get Gloria's
liver. Joe criticized Lucas for being
too bold. If Conrad knew about this,
Lucas would be sued. Unexpectedly, Henry
told Lucas that this was the best thing
he had ever done. Seeing this, Joe could
only pretend not to hear anything. They
quickly discovered that the amount of
phenotin in Gloria's body was three
times the normal dose. But according to
the analysis of her liver damage, it was
used 3 hours before the party started.
Gloria's nurse became the biggest
suspect. At the same time, Hansen said
that Gloria's will had been announced.
Gloria's nurse got all the property.
Everyone immediately thought of murder
and robbery. But through investigation
and interrogation by the police, it was
found that the nurse had taken care of
Gloria for 20 years and had been devoted
to her. Her testimony was also not a
problem. It was just that they had
dinner as usual before the party. It was
clearly over 20°, but Gloria still felt
very cold. The nurse even lit a fire to
keep Gloria warm. Henry suddenly thought
of something, so he rushed to Gloria's
villa. Then he found an unburned piece
of paper in her fireplace. Maybe the
name FC was exactly the same as the
anonymous painting in the gallery.
Suddenly, a scream woke Henry up. The
collector discovered a set of antique
champagne glasses that were missing one.
Henry knew Gloria never drank alcohol,
but the lack of a glass was a little
hard to explain. Henry found the missing
champagne glass in the trunk of the car
along with a bottle of fenny toin. Henry
put all the previous clues together and
suddenly he understood. Henry informed
everyone and went to the museum to tell
them that Gloria had done something
stupid. The autopsy results showed that
Gloria only had a few months to live.
Gloria knew this, so she planned to die.
The reason Gloria chose the night of the
party was because it was a celebration
of her favorite place and where she
could be closest to the person she loved
the most. Gloria knew she didn't have
much time left, so she left party.
Unexpectedly, Gloria was stopped by her
niece and the boyfriend. In addition,
the drug took effect early, causing
Gloria to fall down the stairs. Gloria
endured unimaginable pain. She crawled 3
m only to die in front of the painting
signed by FC because she loved the
artist. Conrad also said that his father
once told him that his mother loved a
young artist. After he found out, he
threatened her that he would destroy
everything the artist had. She then
compromised and stayed. He was so proud
of winning her back that he never
expected that he could only keep her
person but not her heart. Even when he
died, Gloria never forgave him.
Fortunately, Gloria was able to be with
the man she loved in her last moments,
which can be considered a sad story with
a happy ending. Henry did not want to
enter this museum before because he did
not want to recall the past. Under
Gloria's influence, Henry proposed to
his wife here. They swore that they
would love each other forever.
Unfortunately, his wife did not have an
immortal body like him. She passed away
early, leaving him with only sad
memories. The movie ends here. Thank you
for watching. Goodbye and see you