Heat. Heat.
The story took place in Kansas in the
year 2044 and it focused on a young man
named Joe who worked as a specialized
hitman known as a looper where he had a
unique job to kill targets sent back
from the future. That evening he had
just killed his target and after that he
checked the body where he found four
bars of pure silver strapped to his back
as payment for the task. After that, he
only needed to take the body to an
incinerator to dispose of all evidence
of the crime. At the same time, the
world Joe lived in did not yet possess
the technology for time travel because
that concept was still considered
impossible in 2044. However, by the year
2074, which was 30 years later, time
travel had somehow successfully become a
reality. However, because the government
and society in the future did not
approve of time travel, the use of time
machines was strictly limited. This
caused only secret criminal
organizations to continue to use the
technology for their own gain. In that
future era, tracking technology was so
advanced that any crime could be easily
solved by the authorities. And because
of this, it was very difficult for
criminals to commit murders and dispose
of bodies without being caught. That was
why to solve this problem, a criminal
leader named Abe came up with a clever
idea where he traveled back to the year
2044 to establish a criminal
organization called the Loopers. He then
recruited several young men with
incredible killing talents to act as
executioners where their responsibility
was to end the lives of people sent back
from the future, making the victims
disappear forever without the government
ever finding the bodies. For criminals
in the future, there was no way to
escape authorities. And so Abee's
innovation was a great help. This was
because the technology used by the
police in the future was really
advanced, which meant that even the
smallest traces of a crime could be
easily discovered. Because of this, it
was nearly impossible to simply bury a
body or throw it into a river without
getting caught. Especially because the
targets were not just ordinary people,
as they were often powerful figures with
powers like businessmen or corrupt
officials who had a strong influence in
society. So to dispose of them, the
criminal organizations had to send these
people back in time to ensure they
vanished without a single piece of
evidence remaining in the future. That
day, after finishing his work, Joe went
to the Looper headquarters to deposit
his earnings, which was the four bars of
pure silver he found strapped on the
body. But he only handed over two of
them to the organization. And because of
this habit, he became very wealthy and
was able to buy an expensive car, which
was an amazing achievement because the
economy for most people at that time was
very bad and difficult. At the
headquarters, Joe met his fellow hitman
named Seth. He was a man born with a
unique ability called telekinesis which
allowed him to move objects without
touching them. However, most people with
this power could only float small items
like coins or other light objects. The
ability itself was not very useful for
combat and most people only used it for
showing off or trying to impress people.
This showed that evolution in that year
had made 10% of the world's population
born with these natural and unique
talents. After arriving at the criminal
organization's headquarters, Joe
received news about one of his
colleagues who had recently received a
massive payout. This happened because
the target the colleague had to kill was
actually his own future self sent back
from the future. This happened because
of one problem. Since time travel was
strictly illegal and highly dangerous,
the criminal syndicate could not risk
having former loopers become witnesses
for the police. So once a looper reached
the end of his contract or became too
old to do his job properly, the
organization would send him back 30
years to be executed by his younger
self. And this process was known as
closing the loop, which ensured that no
secrets could ever be revealed to the
authorities. However, despite this risk,
people like Joe and Seth were willing to
perform this task because the payment
for killing their future selves was a
lot worth eight bars of solid gold. And
they still believed that they could
change their future and perhaps die in a
different way later in life. That night,
their colleague who had just killed his
future self invited everyone to a party
and they drink even used drugs during
the party. This is when it was shown
that in the future the loopers used a
new and more efficient way to consume
drugs by simply dropping the drugs in
the form of liquid into their eyes.
Unfortunately though, because of this
highincome lifestyle, many of them lived
recklessly while waiting for their own
turn to close their loops. While one by
one, the loopers received their high
payouts and retired early to enjoy the
next 30 years of their lives, believing
that they were living the best possible
life until the day their older selves
would eventually be sent back to the
past to be killed. While the other
hitmen seemed happy with their reality,
Joe, however, became deeply worried
about what his own future would hold. He
began to wonder if his fate was already
set or if a person could actually change
their fate after knowing they were
destined to be shot by their younger
self. These thoughts haunted him and
made his life feel like a confusing
mess. One night, while Joe was trying to
sleep, Seth suddenly appeared at his
place, and he looked really terrified.
It took some time before he could
finally calm down and finally explain
the situation. He revealed that it was
his turn to close his loop by killing
his older self sent from the future.
However, during the execution, the older
version of him began to sing a song
which caused him to feel unexpected
sympathy. Then, instead of finishing the
job quickly, he became distracted when
his older self started telling stories
about what was happening in the future.
His older self also explained that the
entire Looper organization was facing a
serious problem where not only were they
opposed by the government and society,
but they were also being terrorized by a
mysterious and dangerous new figure. And
this person was hunting down all the
hitmen and trying to shut down time
travel forever. Because of this shocking
story, Seth lost his concentration and
allowed his older self to escape while
he was now living in constant fear
because he knew the organization would
kill him if they found out that his
target was still alive and wandering in
the city. Then, since Joe was the only
friend Seth had, he decided to help Seth
by letting him hide in his hideout,
which was a small gap below his floor
where he usually kept all the silver
bars he had earned from his previous
jobs. Soon after, people from the Looper
organization arrived because they
already suspected that Seth would seek
help from Joe. However, because they
couldn't find Seth in his house, they
immediately took Joe to the headquarters
to meet directly with Abe. Then after a
tense negotiation regarding his future
career in the syndicate, Joe felt that
he had no other choice but to reveal
where his friend was hiding. Meanwhile,
the older version of Seth, who was still
running away, began to experience
horrific changes to his body. He
suddenly lost his finger and his nose
because it turned out that his younger
version was being tortured by the
organization. At the same time, a scar
also appeared on his arm containing a
message that told him to go to a
specific location. But by the time he
arrived, he had lost both of his legs.
Then the person from the organization
finally shot him in the head until he
died. On the other hand, back at the
headquarters, Joe was still not fully
aware of the brutal things the
organization had done to Seth. This
actually happened because Abe did not
care about the well-being of his members
at all, as he only cared about his own
personal interests and the safety of his
business. Because of this, it was only a
matter of time before Joe would face the
same fate. Whether it happened tomorrow
or next month, he knew he would
eventually receive the task to kill his
own future self. A month later, that day
finally arrived, and Joe stood ready to
execute himself, sent from 30 years in
the future. However, the older version
of him managed to escape after shielding
himself with the gold bars on his back.
This caused a massive problem for Joe.
Then, realizing that his life was now in
massive danger, he rushed back to his
home with the intention of grabbing his
saved silver and fleeing as far as
possible. However, when he entered the
house, the organization was already
waiting for him there, and he ended up
falling from his room after trying to
avoid the bullets. At that exact moment,
the older Joe appeared as he had been
secretly following his younger self from
a distance, and he was forced to keep
his younger self alive because if his
younger version died, he would cease to
exist. Because of this, he had to
protect his younger self to avoid
suffering a terrible death like Seth.
After bringing Joe to a safe place, the
older version of him went to a public
library to use a computer and searched
for three specific targets who were
still young children at that time. After
that, he printed their information onto
paper to keep track of them. Soon after,
a scar suddenly appeared on his arm and
the scar formed a message from his
younger self who wanted to meet at a
cafe they both frequently visited. This
was a historic moment for them because
it was the first time they sat face to
face as the same person separated by 30
years. During this meeting, the older
Joe shared the story of how his life had
originally played out. He explained that
when it was his turn to kill his future
self, he had completed the task without
any problems. Then, after he officially
retired with a large amount of gold, he
spent years traveling to different
countries, wasting his money, and
drinking heavily. He even worked as an
independent hitman for a while until he
finally met a kind woman from China who
became his devoted wife. It was because
of her love that he completely stopped
his life of crime, drugs, and violence.
However, his happiness did not last
forever because one day, while he was
enjoying his peaceful life with his
wife, news began to spread about a
mysterious figure called the Rain Maker,
who had successfully taken control of
the five largest criminal syndicates in
the future and was hunting down every
retired looper. Then, at one point,
members of the syndicate sent by the
rain maker eventually arrived at older
Joe's home with the intention of taking
him to their headquarters. However,
during that encounter, something
terrible happened when the syndicate
accidentally shot his wife and killed
her. After that, when Joe was about to
be sent back to the past for his
execution, he managed to fight back
against his capttors and decided to use
the time machine anyway to travel back
to 2044 because he wanted to prevent the
death of his beloved wife by killing the
rain maker while he was still a kid.
Then, using coordinates provided by one
of his friends, the older Joe intended
to find the boy who would eventually
become the powerful rain maker. And even
though it was a heavy burden to take the
life of a minor, he remained determined
to do it for the sake of his wife.
However, the younger Joe was stubborn
and refused to cooperate with his older
self. Because of this disagreement, the
older Joe was forced to use violence
just as the organization's men arrived
at the scene.
But instead of helping his future self,
the younger Joe actually chose to side
with the organization and hunted the
older man until he managed to escape.
The younger Joe then tried to chase
older Joe on a motorcycle, but he ended
up crashing and falling through thick
fields. Because of this, he had to
continue his search on foot using a
piece of paper he had managed to grab
from his older self earlier. The paper
led the younger Joe to a farm that
belonged to a woman named Sarah who was
a single parent who lived alone with her
young son. However, because Joe was
unsure of how to approach her, he waited
for an opportunity to reveal himself. He
eventually got the chance to help Sarah
when she was being threatened by a
homeless person. At that moment, Joe
himself was suffering from withdrawal
because he had not used his illegal
drugs for a while. And because she felt
sorry for him and grateful for saving
her, Sarah took him into her home and
began to treat him properly. The next
morning, as soon as Joe woke up, Sarah
pointed her shotgun at him and demanded
to know why he had come to her farm.
Because of the tension between them, Joe
finally decided to be honest about his
identity and the situation he was facing
by explaining that he was there to wait
for someone who would arrive soon to
kill a child. He told her that this
person was searching for the boy who
would eventually become the rain maker
in the future, which in this case was
Sarah's only son, Sid. However, at the
same time, he did not reveal that the
person coming to kill Sid was actually
his own older self from the future.
After that, Joe persuaded Sarah to
cooperate with him so they could wait
together for the arrival of the man who
wanted to harm her son. Then, while they
waited at the farm, the older Joe began
his hunt by going to the first address
on his list. And although it felt like a
heavy burden and went against his
personal principles, he felt that he had
no choice but to commit the act. Because
of his deep love for his wife, he was
willing to do anything to bring her back
and change the future. At the same time,
back at Sarah's house, Joe spent time
getting to know Sid. It was unclear if
this young boy was truly the one
destined to become the rain maker.
However, when Joe talked to him, he
responded like an adult, and it was
revealed that his intelligence was far
above average, which he proved by
building a warning alarm out of old toy
parts. Not long after, a hitman from the
organization arrived at the farm
searching for the younger Joe and the
man forced his way into the house which
left Sarah feeling completely helpless.
Not long after that, Joe came down from
the upper floor and upon seeing Sarah in
danger, he claimed that he was ready to
cooperate. He even offered to trade
several bars of silver in exchange for
his life, hoping to settle the matter
peacefully. However, before the
negotiation could finish, the hitman was
startled by Sid, who also came down the
stairs. Unfortunately, because the boy
was frightened by the stranger, he
accidentally tripped and fell. But
instead of rushing to help her son,
Sarah immediately pulled Joe out of the
house because she knew what was about to
happen. It was then revealed that like
Seth and the other 10% of the
population, Sid was born with natural
telekinetic abilities. The difference
was that he possessed a version of the
power that was far stronger than anyone
else's. By using his power, the objects
inside the house began to float and
shake violently, and that showed how
great his power was. because he could
not control his anger, Sid then used his
mind to cause the hitman's body to
explode from the inside. Meanwhile,
seeing such powerful power from a small
child made it clear that Sid was indeed
the future rain maker. However, although
Joe briefly thought about killing the
boy because he was so dangerous, he
realized that he did not have the heart
to do it. So, instead of letting the
situation get worse, he urged Sarah to
take her son and run as far away as
possible from there. At the same time,
one of the organization's members
managed to find CCTV footage showing the
older Joe in action. And after a short
investigation, the syndicate
successfully captured the older Joe and
brought him directly to their main
headquarters. Shortly after, upon
arriving at the headquarters, the guards
got into a small argument about who
should present the prisoner to Abe. And
because of this distraction, the older
Joe found the perfect moment to strike
back. He then showed his elite skills as
a hitman by killing Abe and slaughtering
every other hitman in the building.
After that, with the organization
destroyed, he immediately headed toward
the farm where Sid was hiding. But when
he arrived, the younger Joe was already
there waiting for him in the middle of
the road. Suddenly, a member of the
organization appeared and he somehow
survived the earlier chaos. However, the
younger Joe managed to kill him, but
during the fight, he lost track of the
older version of himself. On the other
hand, just as Sarah and Sid were
attempting to drive away, it turned out
that the older Joe had tracked them
down. He then began firing his weapon at
their vehicle to stop them. And this
made Sid terrified and instinctively
used his telekinetic powers, which
caused their car to flip over.
[sighs] Sarah and Sid then got out of
the wreckage and ran into the middle of
the fields, but the older Joe continued
to hunt them down with his gun. At that
moment, because Sid was pushed to his
emotional limit once again, his powerful
telekinesis began to surge and it shook
everything around them.
However, to calm her son, Sarah showed
incredible patience and eventually
managed to calm her son's anger with her
gentle words. However, even after seeing
how powerful Sid was, the older Joe
remained determined to kill him. At that
exact moment, the younger Joe soon
arrived and realized a shocking truth.
He finally connected the dots that the
person responsible for creating the rain
maker was actually his own future self
who at that moment was about to kill
Sarah. The older man would give Sid
trauma and hatred that turned him into a
monster in the future. Because of this,
to break this endless loop, the younger
Joe made a brave and shocking decision.
He realized that if he ended his own
life in the present, then his older self
would immediately cease to exist and
would never be able to pull the trigger.
Thanks to his sacrifice, the older Joe
finally vanished into thin air and Sarah
was saved. Then after these events, she
continued to raise her son with great
love and care. And because he never lost
his mother and never felt the need for
revenge, the future where Rain Maker
existed never